賽艇男孩
翻譯：三塊一毛七 / 微博：三塊一毛七x
喬爾·埃哲頓
卡勒姆·特納
彼得·吉尼斯
傑克·馬赫恩
詹姆斯·沃克
哈德莉·羅賓遜
考特尼·海根勒
山姆·斯特萊特
托馬斯·埃爾姆斯
盧克·斯拉特裏
用力
Press.
蹬腿
Legs through.
團結一致
Stay together.
上下一心
As one.
入水 破水
In. Through.
蹬腿
Legs through.
夥計
Oh, man!
什麼鬼
What the heck?
我發誓那小子會害死我的
I swear that boy's gonna be the death of me.
每次我一修好他又給弄壞
Every time I fix it, he rips it again.
西雅圖 華盛頓 1936年
工程設計不同於
Engineering design is different
其他創意領域
from other areas of creativity
在這個領域裏 你必須能夠真正構建你想像的東西
in that, you must be able to actually build what you imagine.
並確保它符合你的設計
And then make sure it works as you designed.
設計流程圖有助於引導你的創造力
The design process is structured to help direct your creativity.
好了...
Now, uh...
你想成為哪種工程師
What kinda engineer you wanna be?
我覺得我想成為機械工程師 因為我喜歡造東西
I'm thinking mechanical for me'cause I like building things.
- 嗯哼 - 你想結伴...
- Mm- hmm. - You wanna partner up on...
你們兩位有什麼想和我們分享的嗎
Something you two gentlemen would like to share with us?
還是讓我繼續
Or can I continue?
抱歉
Sorry.
- 多謝 - 太棒了 謝謝
- Thank you. - Awesome. Thank you.
我還需要一個人
Okay, I just need one more.
讓我看看
Let's see.
你
Uh, you.
今天就需要這麼多人 抱歉了 夥計們
That's all I need today, fellas. Sorry.
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
我今天早上在信箱裏發現了這個
This was in my box this morning.
看起來你這個學期的學費還未結清
Okay, it looks like you still owe a balance on this semester.
是這樣 我付了一半的學費
Yeah, well, I paid half already
他們說剩下的一半可以晚點交
and they said I could pay the other half later.
恐怕已經不能再晚了 蘭茨先生
Afraid later has arrived, Mr. Rantz.
也許兼職會有所幫助
Maybe a part- time job would help.
我一直在找
I've been looking.
走廊那頭有塊招工板
Well, there's a board down the hall.
我可以寬限你兩周的時間
I can give you two weeks.
在那之後 你會需要考慮一下轉學
After that, you will need to consider other educational options.
謝了
Thanks.
這是在浪費時間 上面的號碼我都打過了
It's a waste of time. I called every number up here.
還有這個保姆的工作
And that nanny job,
還沒開學就已經招滿了
all filled before semester even started.
我每天都來看一下 希望有新的機會
I check every day to get a jump on a new one,
但希望渺茫
but there hadn't been any.
在我租得起房子之前 我和我阿姨住在一起
I'm staying with my aunt till I can afford a place.
我要花半天的時間清理我衣服上的貓毛
I spend half my day pulling cat hair off of my clothes.
我討厭貓
I hate cats.
你喜歡它們嗎
You like'em?
我是說貓
Cats, I mean.
我沒怎麼想過它們
I, uh, never thought much about'em.
我討厭它們
I hate'em.
我就說在課上看見了你
Thought I saw you in class.
- 你還記得我嗎 - 嗯哼
- You remember me? - Mm- hmm.
好吧 那我叫什麼名字
All right. Then, what's my name?
喬伊斯·桑德斯
Uh, Joyce Simdars.
- 而你是喬·蘭茨 - 是
- And you're Joe Rantz. - Uh- huh.
我記得你是因為四年級的時候
I remember because you had a huge crush on me
你很喜歡我
in the fourth grade.
- 我才沒有 - 你有
- No, I didn't. - Yeah, yeah, you did.
你給我做了一張漂亮的小卡片
You made me this pretty little card
裏面還塞了一些花
with some flowers stuffed in it.
就在我的家人搬去奧林匹亞之前
Right before my family went away to Olympia.
- 呃... - 你是那種人嗎
- Uh... - Are you one of those people
就是緊張的時候會吃不下飯
who can't eat when you're nervous?
- 我不緊張 - 是嗎
- I'm not nervous. - No?
那麼 你來這裏幹什麼
So, what are you doing here, Joe?
我想學習工程學
I'm trying to learn, uh, engineering.
我會成為一名教師
I'm gonna be a teacher.
不過來這裏主要是為了遠離家
Mostly here just to get away from home, though.
你記得我媽媽嗎
You remember my mother?
有印象 她手上總是拿著本聖經
Sorta. Always had a Bible in her hand.
對
Yeah.
除非她把它扔你臉上
Unless she's throwing it at you.
你喜歡划艇嗎
You like rowboats?
就是劃它們
You know, like, paddlin''em.
- 你是誰 - 我是羅傑
- Who's this? - I'm Roger.
你好 羅傑 我是喬伊斯
Hi, Roger. I'm Joyce.
這是喬 但他現在不怎麼說話
This is Joe, but he's not real talkative right now
因為他有點緊張
'cause he's a little bit nervous.
- 我沒有 我才不緊張 - 他有點小緊張
- No, I'm not. No, I'm not. - He is a little nervous.
我不緊張
I'm not nervous.
如果你會划艇的話我們也許能賺到些錢
We might be able to make some money if you can row.
- 喬伊斯 你好了嗎 - 得走了 夥計們
- Joyce, you ready? - Oh. Gotta go, boys.
很高興再次見到你 喬
Nice seeing you again, Joe.
羅傑
Roger.
對了
By the way,
你現在還喜歡我嗎
did you ever get over that crush?
來吧 我們走
Come on, let's go.
她很漂亮 是嗎
She's a looker, huh?
你說的賺錢是怎麼回事
So, what's that about making some money?
就是賽艇隊
Yeah, the rowing team.
如果入選了 你就能得到一份兼職工作
You're on it, you get a part- time job
包括一個便宜的住處
including a cheap place to live.
我可以擺脫那些貓
I could get free of them cats.
只要你能加入賽艇隊
All you gotta do is make the team.
這能有多難
How hard can that be?
華盛頓大學學生會船屋
賽艇隊有多少人
How many make the team?
嘿 有多少...
Hey, how many, uh...
有多少人能入選
How many fellas get picked?
我想是八個人
Eight, I think.
八個
Eight?
他怎麼說
What's he say?
他不知道
He didn't know.
好了 豎起你們的耳朵
All right, listen up.
我是烏爾布裏克森教練
I'm Coach Ulbrickson.
這是博爾思教練
Well, that's Coach Bolles,
布朗教練
Coach Brown.
你們今天來這是因為
Now, you're all here because we're looking
我們在尋找八個最有資格的人組成我們的賽艇隊
for the eight most qualified young men to fill out JV boat.
也就是說你們當中的大部分人會落選
That means most of you will not be chosen.
實際上 你們大多數人極有可能
In fact, the majority of you will most likely
在接下來的幾周內自行離開
walk away on your own within the next few weeks,
因為你們的身體會受傷
'cause your bodies will hurt,
心神會疲憊
minds will tire,
你們不禁會覺得
and you'll decide this dream of yours
與世界上最偉大的選手競爭的夢想
to compete against the greatest crews in the world
根本不值一提
is just not worth it.
這沒什麼丟人的
There's no shame in that.
八人賽艇
Eight- man crew
是世界上最困難的團體運動
is the most difficult team sport in the world.
一般人的身體不適合做這些事情
The average human body is just not meant for such things.
力所不能及
It's just not capable of such things.
但我的艇上不會有平庸之輩的一席之地
But average is not gonna get a seat on my boat.
祝你們好運
So, good luck.
好了 排成兩行
Okay. Fall into two lines.
登記在左邊 領制服在右邊
Registration on the left. Uniforms on the right.
你的演講很精彩 教練
That was a beautiful speech, Coach.
- 名字 - 喬·蘭茨
- Name? - Uh, Joe Rantz.
喬 之前當過賽艇選手嗎
Joe, you ever crewed before?
划艇 之前劃過艇嗎
Row. You ever rowed before?
沒...
No. No. Uh...
賽艇隊的工資有多少
How much does the job pay once you're on the team?
去那邊拿你的裝備
Go pick up your gear over there.
- 在右邊 下一個 - 名字
- To your right. Next. - Name?
羅傑·莫裏斯
Roger Morris.
羅傑 之前當過賽艇選手嗎
Roger, you ever crewed before?
沒有
No.
好了
All right.
在對面拿你的裝備
Pick up your gear across the way.
你們會被分成兩組
You'll be divided into groups
輪崗訓練
and rotate through training stations.
念到你的編號時 跟著教練走
When you hear your number called, follow the coach.
1到16號 你們跟著我
One through 16, you're with me,
17到32號跟著馬修斯教練
17 through 32 with Coach Matthews,
33到48號跟著我
33 to 48 with me.
排好隊
Line up.
你知道我們要面對什麼嗎
You got any idea what we're in for?
不知道
I don't know.
很好 我也不知道
Good. Me either.
1到16號 過來
One through 16, come on.
一般的成年男子
The average adult man is capable
能夠每分鐘吸入大約四升氧氣
of taking in roughly four liters of oxygen per minute.
一個槳手必須能吸入並消耗多達八升
An oarsman must be able to consume as much as eight.
你必須訓練自己的身體做到這一點
You have to teach your bodies to do that.
我們做50個俯臥撐
We'll do 50 push- ups,
然後是50個仰臥起坐和50個千斤頂
followed by 50 sit- ups and 50 jacks.
連續做50組
We'll keep doing sets of 50
直到換崗為止
till it's time to change stations.
每邊八個人
Eight on each side.
腳放在蹬板上
Feet in stretchers.
繫好鞋帶
Lace'em up.
讓我們和老尼祿好好玩玩
Let's take Old Nero out.
好了 聽我指令 挺直腰板 用上你的大腿
All right, on my count, straight backs, use your legs.
12號 別光拍打水面 轉動你的手腕
Twelve! Don't just slap the water. Roll your wrists.
起 臥
Up, down.
四 五 六 七
Four, five, six, seven,
八 九 十
eight, nine, ten.
劃 二 三 四
Stroke, two, three, four.
提槳 划槳 拉槳 回槳
Catch, drive, finish, recovery.
下一崗 所有人都下艇
Next station. Everybody out.
起 臥
Up, down.
交換位置
Switch!
準備就緒
All set?
起 臥
Up, down.
划槳有四個步驟 小伙子們
There's four parts to a stroke, gentlemen,
不是三個 明白嗎
not three, okay?
提槳 划槳 拉槳 回槳
Catch, drive, finish, and recovery.
你不能跳過任何一個步驟
You can't skip any of'em.
你們知道我們為什麼走不了直線嗎
And you know why we're not going in a straight line?
因為22號
'Cause number 22 here
是唯一一個把我的話聽進去的人
is the only one that's listening to me.
提槳 划槳
Catch, drive,
拉槳 回槳
finish, recovery.
好點了
That's better.
好了 我們把槳頻提到18
All right. Let's pick up the pace to 18.
這群人可真夠高大 的 教練
Lot of tall timber in this bunch, Coach.
很少有男生能比得上你的賽艇隊
Few boys there could even push your varsity crew.
一天的時間很難說明什麼
It's hard to judge off one day.
儘管如此 你肯定非常滿意
Still, you had to see enough
因為你差點就笑顏逐開了
to make you almost finally crack a smile?
賽季末我會告訴你的
Yeah, I'll let you know at the end of the season, huh?
今年可是奧運年
Olympic year, this year,
所以理想上看 他們會比大多數人有更多機會
so ideally, they'll stretch longer than most.
奧運年嗎 我都沒意識到
Olympic year? I didn't realize.
我和加州的埃布萊特教練談過了
I spoke with Coach Ebright down in Cali.
他肯定是意識到了
He's sure aware of it.
他對自己的賽艇隊也很有信心
Feels good about his chances, too.
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
你想在報紙上看到什麼樣的第一印象
Any first impressions you'd like to see in print?
你知道我不讀報的 羅亞爾
You know I don't read the paper, Royal.
打擾一下 教練
Excuse me, Coach.
如果你是找我要竅門 你得和其他人一樣在練習中熟能生巧
If you're looking for tips, you're gonna have to get 'em in practice like everybody else.
不是的 教練 我只是想知道這份工作的工資有多少
No, sir. I was just wondering how much this paid.
再說一遍
Say again?
他們說如果入選了賽艇隊就能得到一份工作
They said there was a job included if you make the team?
我只想知道這筆錢夠不夠付我剩下的學費
I just need to know if it's gonna cover the rest of my tuition.
我相信肯定夠了
Yeah, I'm sure it will.
你現在只需要專心致志
Hey, you just concentrate for now
- 爭取進入賽艇隊 小子 - 多謝教練
- on making the squad, son. - Thank you, sir.
這個問題我打賭
Now, there's a question I bet
那些常春藤名校的教練都沒遇到過
those Ivy League coaches never get.
話說回來
Speakin' of,
我真心希望今年的情況能比去年好
I sure hope this year goes better than the last.
沒有人比我更支持你的隊員了
No one's rooting for your boys more than me.
- 祝你好運 教練 - 你也是 羅亞爾
- Good luck, Coach. - And you, Royal.
你吃過什麼東西了嗎
Did you go grab some food?
我不餓
Ah, I'm not hungry.
如果你想要的話 我的食物足夠我們倆吃了
I got enough for us both if you want it.
還沒餓到那個地步
Not that hungry.
一會見了
I'll see you later.
非常感謝
I appreciate it.
給你
There you go.
給你 先生 多謝
Here you go, sir. Thank you.
- 雞肉嘗起來怎麼樣 - 什麼
- How's your chicken? - Hmm?
味道很好 謝了
Great. Thanks.
可你吃的是豬肉
Yeah, that's a pork chop you're eating.
抱歉
Sorry.
今天我看見羅亞爾·布魯姆了
So, I saw Royal Brougham today.
他一定要告訴我
And he made sure to tell me
凱爾·埃布萊特的賽艇隊今年十分強勢
that Ky Ebright's squad is strong this year.
加州大學一直都很強勢
Cal is always strong.
你總是憂心忡忡
And you always worry.
你的新隊員看起來怎麼樣
How'd your new boys look?
現在下定論還為時尚早
Well, it's too early to say.
報名的人很多
There's definitely a lot of 'em.
這很好 一個很不錯的大馬廄供我選擇
That's good. Nice big stable to choose from.
- 如果有足夠的人能堅持下來 - 強者必勝
- If enough of them last. - The best ones will.
和你當年一樣
Just like you did.
你們怎麼了
What's wrong with you?
沒什麼 只是有點酸痛
Nothing, just a little stiff.
看起來是這樣 怎麼回事
Yeah, looks it. How come?
劃艇划到生命殆盡
Rowed boats till it almost killed us.
什麼
What?
翻到教材的43頁
Page 43 in your texts.
所以 在求解框架時
So, in solving the framework,
反射意味著什麼
what does it mean to reflect?
打擾一下 年輕人
Excuse me, young man.
你想讓我講得小聲點好讓你休息嗎
Would you like me to speak quieter so you can rest?
我覺得這是一個陷阱問題
I feel like that's maybe a trick question.
安靜
Quiet!
專心聽講 否則就回家睡覺
Pay attention or go home to sleep.
魚和熊掌不可兼得
You can't do both in here.
不用謝 喬·蘭茨
You're welcome, Joe Rantz.
謝謝
Thank you.
三
Three.
四
Four.
推 拉 推...
Push, then pull. Push...
起 臥
Up, down!
48號和12號坐艇頭
48 and 12 on the bow.
我在想...
Yeah. I'm thinkin'...
莫裏斯坐第六位怎麼樣 就在蘭茨後面
What about Morris in the six behind Rantz?
跟著我的節奏
Keep time with me.
劃 二 三 四 劃 二 三 四 劃 二...
Stroke, two, three, four. Stroke, two...
加把勁 夥計們 拿出你們吃奶的力氣
Come on, boys! Who wants it more?
蹬腿別停
Keep driving those legs!
別讓22號打敗你
Do not let 22 beat you!
你還記得我嗎
You still remember me?
嗯哼
Mm- hmm.
我不太確定
Wasn't sure.
最近沒怎麼見到你
Haven't seen you much lately.
我只是在忙些事情
I just been busy with stuff.
- 划艇的事嗎 - 大部分是
- Rowing stuff? - Mostly.
我聽見羅傑說他們今天就要宣佈賽艇隊的名單了
I heard Roger say that they're announcing the team today.
你會入選嗎
Are you gonna make it?
很多人都想入選
There's lot of guys tryin'.
等你進去後 你想載我去兜個風嗎
You wanna take me on a boat ride when you do?
當然
Sure.
先生們
Gentlemen,
我想感謝大家的到來
I wanna thank you all for comin' out
感謝你們全力以赴
and giving your best effort.
留下來站在這的每一個人
Every single one of you left standing
都令人欽佩
has performed admirably.
遺憾是 你們中只有少數人才能被選中
Unfortunately, only a few of you can be chosen to continue.
博爾思教練
Coach Bolles.
休謨
Hume.
亨特
Hunt.
麥克米林
McMillin.
戴
Day.
莫裏斯
Morris.
懷特
White.
亞當
Adam.
蘭茨
Rantz.
科伊 你是後備隊員
Coy, you're the reserve.
謝謝你們的到來以及所付出的努力
We thank the rest of you for your time and your effort.
就這樣吧
All right, then.
好好慶祝一番
Go and celebrate.
明天水上不見不散
I will see you on the water tomorrow.
好樣的
Well done.
這是我最喜歡的部分
That's my favorite part.
動作快點 各位
Come on, boys.
該走了
Let's go.
把槳舉起來
Now lift 'em up.
他總是對自己的閃避技巧滔滔不絕
It's all this guy talks about, his Dodge.
嘿 在划艇方面我可是個老司機了
Hey, listen, I've done so much rowing.
我就知道你能行
I knew you'd made it.
我們當中有一個入選我就很高興了
I'm glad one of us did.
你永遠是那個天選之子
Ah, you were always in the bag.
但是教練念到我名字的時候 我差點就跪了下來
When Coach called my name, my knees almost buckled.
不知道他們會把我們分到哪個座位上
I wonder what seats they'll put us in.
我只想做領槳手
I just want the stroke.
那個位置已經是休謨的囊中之物了
That's Hume's seat. Guaranteed.
嘿 你不是一個啞巴吧
Hey, you're not a mute, are you?
因為你一直都沒出聲
'Cause I've never once heard you say nothin'.
不是
No.
以他划槳的樣子 他用不著說話
He doesn't need to talk, the way he pulls that oar.
對啊 恰克 如果你想當領槳手的話 也該少說點話
Yeah, Chuck, maybe you should pull more and talk less, you want that stroke seat.
他們要我在哪個位置都行
I don't care where they put me,
只要讓我在艇上就行
as long as I'm in there somewhere.
我們都會在艇上的
We're all in there somewhere.
好嘛
Yeah.
華盛頓大學校歌《Bow Down To Washington》
臣服於華盛頓吧
Bow down to Washington
臣服於華盛頓
紫金長袍加身的人啊叱吒風雲
Mighty are the men who wear the purple and the gold
熱烈歡迎他們投入勝利者的懷抱
Joyfully we welcome them within the victor's fold
我們的事跡將名垂青史
We will carve our names in the Hall of Fame
我們的忠誠流芳百世
To preserve the memory of our devotion
願上帝保佑華盛頓的敵人
So, heaven help the foes of Washington
華盛頓的大名讓他們膽戰心驚
They're trembling at the feet of mighty Washington
我們的勇士鳴響號角 他們勢如破竹無人能擋
Our boys are there with bells Their fighting blood excels
他們堅韌不拔恪守戰場
It's harder to push them over the lines than pass...
- 嘿 - 你好呀
- Hey. - Hi.
你...
You, uh...
你想乘艇兜風嗎
You wanna go for a boat ride?
現在嗎
Now?
對啊
Yeah.
好吧 來了
Yeah, okay.
提槳 划槳
Catch, drive,
拉槳 回槳
finish, recovery.
你得完成全部四個步驟才能前進
You gotta do all four before you can start again.
平槳：賽艇運動技術術語。是指運動員將槳葉平放在水面上，平槳時運動員身體放鬆，槳葉背面著水，槳葉的前面向天。
平槳也是一種口令，當運動員在划槳中，遇到障礙物或靠近碼頭需 要停止划槳時，舵手或教練員可以用「平槳」口令，要運動員停 止划槳。
好點了 下一步你得平槳
That's better. You gotta feather next.
平槳 什麼是平槳
Feathering? What's feather?
讓我演示給你看
Here, look.
轉動你的手腕
You roll your wrists
來轉動槳
to spin the oar.
- 看到了嗎 - 嗯
- You see? - Mm.
現在再試一次
Now, try again.
你真是天賦異稟
You're a natural.
我以為你才是划槳的而我是看風景的
I thought you said you were gonna take me on a boat ride.
好吧 靠過去
All right, scooch over.
看我的
All right.
你喜歡划艇嗎
Do you like it? Rowing?
額
Well,
划艇給了我一份工作
gettin' a job out of it.
還給了我一個棲身之所
And a room. So, I guess.
你們隊伍裏還有誰
Who else made the team?
羅傑 小矮個 還有其他一些人
Roger, Shorty, some others.
你知道嗎 他們會在收音機裏播報比賽
You know, they put the races on the radio.
萬人空巷
Everybody listens.
我知道 他們還會拍照
Yeah, they took, uh, some photos.
- 問一大堆的問題 - 什麼樣的問題
- Asked a bunch of questions. - What kinds of questions?
就是一般的問題
It's just, you know,
我們從哪來之類的
where we're from, stuff like that.
你們會說真話嗎
Did you tell them the truth?
大多數吧
Mm. Mostly.
你們到時肯定會聲名大噪
You're all gonna be famous.
那時候我便會成為過眼雲煙
Then you really will forget about me.
我覺得即使我想忘也忘不掉
I don't think I could if I tried.
你得把我們劃回岸邊
You get to row us back to shore.
我們明天早上還有課
We have class in the morning.
- 你想要哪張床 - 我無所謂
- Which bed you want? - Couldn't care less.
真舒服
Oh, nice.
這些床是我們的了吧
We get to keep these, right?
只要你還是賽艇隊的一員
Long as we stay on the team.
艇上的每個位置都有其特定的作用
Each seat on the boat has its own purpose.
就好比八個不同的部位組成一匹強大的賽馬
Like eight separate parts of one great racehorse.
莫裏斯一號位 戴二號位
Morris in one, Day in two,
亞當三號位
and Adam in the three.
一般來說，一號位和二號位技術細膩，是平衡掌控者，確保艇的穩定性
你們的技術會保持這艘艇的正確航向
Your technique will keep the boat on its proper course.
四號位 五號位 六號位 你們就好比機艙
And four, five, and six are like the engine room.
三號位到六號位充當大力水手，給艇提供動力
那是能源所在
That is the power.
由懷特 麥克米林還有亨特擔任
White, McMillin, and Hunt.
蘭茨是我們的七號位
Now, Rantz is our seven.
七號位和八號位（領槳手）在團隊中起著帶領划槳速度和節奏的作用
你和領槳手休謨設定我們的節奏
So, you set the pace with Hume, the stroke.
每一匹優秀的賽馬都有一名騎師
And every good racehorse has a jockey.
格倫·莫裏...
Glenn Morry...
過來 格倫
Come on, Glenn.
舵手位於艇尾，操縱艇行駛的方向，同時制定比賽策略，給槳手提供意見，以保證艇作為一個整體，安全且高效率地行駛，最快到達終點
...是我們的舵手
...is our coxswain.
他按照我和博爾思講練
Now, he calls the strategy
制定的比賽策略給你們提供建議
set up by myself and Coach Bolles.
當他讓你們奔跑的時候 他會給你們韁繩
He'll give you rein when he wants you to run,
他會拉住你們 讓你們放慢速度
he'll pull you back to slow you down.
當時機來臨時 你們便可策艇奔騰
And when the time is right, he'll get out his whip.
嘿 夥計們
Hey, fellas.
好了 到水上去吧
Okay, time to get in the water.
再來一次
Let's go again!
嘿 菜鳥
Hey, junior boat,
第一天累壞你了嗎
you tired after your first day?
- 他撐不下來的 - 別往心裏去
- He'll never make it. - Don't take it so hard.
你要去哪裏 回來啊
Hey, where you going? Come back.
我討厭那些混蛋
I hate those assholes.
你得學會控制自己的節奏
You gotta learn to pace yourself.
- 你是喬 對吧 - 嗯哼
- It's Joe, isn't it? - Mm- hmm.
你們大多數人只有置身於艇上
Most of you boys don't have an interest in a boat
才會提起對一條艇的興趣
until you can sit in it.
你喜歡做木工嗎
You like to work with wood?
對 我父親會做些
Yeah, my father did some.
他以前會造東西
He used to make things.
不過沒有這樣的東西 就門廊和雜物之類的
Nothing like this, just porches and stuff.
有一次我幫他修好了一艘老獨木舟
I helped him fix up an old canoe once.
我相信此刻你父母肯定會為你感到非常驕傲
I'm sure he and your mother must be very proud of you now.
進了賽艇隊
Making the team.
這是給你們準備的
This is for you boys.
你們的賽艇
Your racing shell.
隨時歡迎你來幫我一把
Always welcome to give me a hand with it.
如果你有空的話
If you find some free time.
不是 我不是讓你現在幫
No, I didn't mean right now.
你今晚應該好好休息
You should rest up tonight.
我沒事
I'm okay.
技巧重於力量
Technique is more important than power.
你必須能拉出一次完美的槳
You have to be able to pull a perfect oar,
一次又一次
stroke after stroke.
這叫做用力
It's called swing.
當八個人齊聲划槳時
When all eight are rowing in such perfect unison
每一個人的動作
that no single action
都與艇上的其他部分相協調
is out of sync with the rest of the boat.
到那時你們就不會對抗彼此
Then you aren't fighting each other.
用更少的力前進
You're moving with less effort.
你們的每次划槳
Each one of your strokes is worth
都相當於其他艇划1.5次
one and a half of the other boat's.
大多數選手不知道這一點
Most crews never find it.
但等他們知道後
But when they do,
划艇的詩意就不再局限於運動
rowing is more poetry than sport.
懷特和戴交換位置
White and Day, switch.
蘭茨和亞當
Rantz, Adam,
換回來
switch back.
劃
Row!
- 劃啊 - 使勁啊
- Row! - Come on!
- 劃啊 - 使勁
- 劃 - 劃過這片湖
- Row! - Row through the lake!
劃 再劃
Row! More!
怎麼 你們把過去三年的所學
What, did you forget everything you learned
都拋之腦後了嗎
in the last three years?
布朗 你還是會揚槳
Brown, you're still skying.
比林斯 你是領槳手嗎 急匆匆的幹嘛
Billings, are you the stroke? You're rushing.
你背後的七個人都追趕著你的節奏
You have seven men behind you, all chasing the boat.
每分鐘34次划槳
34 strokes.
34次對你們來說就好了
You're fine at 34 strokes.
比這再高這支隊伍就會分崩離析
Anything higher and you fall apart.
以每分鐘34次的速度 你們贏不了加州大學
34 strokes, you don't beat Cal.
每分鐘34次
34 strokes,
你在波基普西贏不了
you don't win at Poughkeepsie.
更不用說去德國
You certainly don't get to Germany.
你們知道34次贏得了誰嗎
You know who you beat with 34 strokes?
青年隊
The JV boat.
勉勉強強
Maybe.
你們還在等什麼 回艇上去
What are you guys waiting for? Get back in the boat.
你們要回到艇上
You guys, you're gonna get back out there
不停地練習直到你們掌握要領為止
and you're gonna do it again until you get it right!
希望我沒有打擾到你 阿爾
Hope I'm not intruding, Al.
沒有的事 本 進來坐吧
Not at all, Ben. Come on in. Take a seat.
時機剛剛好
Great timing.
正好瀏覽一下設備預算
Just going through the equipment budget
好交給你們委員會
to send over to your committee.
沒什麼不合理的地方
Nothing unreasonable.
給健身房新增了一些設備
Some pieces for the gymnasium.
還有五年前的舊隊服
And the five- year- old uniforms
看起來不免破爛不堪
are startin' to look a little ragged.
我們會盡力而為的
Ah, we'll see what we can do.
委員會下周開會
Committee's meeting next week.
你們贏得越多 校友自然會提供源源不斷的資金
More wins usually means more money from the alumni.
那當然
Sure.
那麼這些小伙子表現怎麼樣 教練
So, how are our boys doing, Coach?
現在還為時尚早 但他們表現很不錯
Early to say, but solid.
他們一直在努力訓練
Oh, they've been workin' hard.
我兒子博 他們休賽期還在訓練
My boy, Bo, had 'em training all off season.
- 他覺得今年能和加州大學掰掰手腕 - 希望我們能
- Think they're gonna make a real run at Cal this year. - I hope we can.
我們也有一支青年隊來推動他們 你該...
We got a good junior boat to push 'em, too. You should...
我們終於可以在自己的地方掛上橫幅了
It'd be nice to finally hang a banner up at our place
而不是讓加州大學搶了所有的風頭
instead of letting Cal have 'em all.
我們會全力以赴的 先生
We'll do our best, sir.
奧運金牌等你們去摘呢
And an Olympic medal to go with it.
博自信他的艇有奪冠的機會
Bo says his boat's got a shot.
前提是我們努力訓練
If we work hard.
並有所突破
And catch some breaks.
人生的突破由勝利者自己創造 教練
Winners make our own breaks in life, Coach.
我們需要這次勝利
And we need this.
機不可失時不再來
It's now or never.
出自莎士比亞著名戲劇《仲夏夜之夢》第五幕第二場，本段採取了朱生豪譯本
"要是我們這輩影子 有拂了諸位的尊意
"If we shadows have offended
"就請你們這樣思量 一切便可得到補償
"Think but this, and all is mended.
"這種種幻景的顯現
"That you have but slumbered here...
"不過是夢中的妄念"
"While these visions did appear."
多謝
Thank you.
語出莎士比亞 對吧
It's some fella called Shakespeare, right?
我說 那些搞音樂的人
You know, music people
真該保管好自己的垃圾
should have to take care of their own trash.
至少比昨晚的餐廳要好
Better than the cafeteria last night.
天 我今天都快吃不下了
I mean, God, I almost couldn't eat today.
你看到那些陳年的食物了嗎 就那樣糊弄在一起
You see that old food, all mushed around like that?
哎
Eugh!
你注意到了嗎 女孩們的桌子下
You ever notice how under the girls' tables,
永遠都是最髒亂的
it's always the worst?
如果你仔細觀察 你會發現女孩子都很邋遢
When you look close, girls are nasty.
你沒注意到是因為她們都紅裝素裹
You don't realize it 'cause of their nice dresses
秀髮翩翩
and their hair's all fixed up.
但我寧願打掃十個男生的桌子 也不...
But I'll clean under 10 boys' tables before I do one...
唐 還有什麼是你不會的嗎
Oh, Don, there anything you can't do?
繼續彈呀
Keep goin'.
《Ain't We Got Fun》- Doris Day
我們不是很開心嗎
Ain't we got fun?
房租還沒付呢 親愛的
The rent's unpaid, dear
我們沒有車
We haven't a car
無論如何 親愛的
In any way, dear
我們就保持本色
We'll stay as we are
即使還欠著雜貨店的錢
Even if we owe the grocer
我們不是很開心嗎
Ain't we got fun?
把莫裏斯放到蘭茨後面的六號位怎麼樣
What about Morris in the six behind Rantz
讓亨特在一號位
and Hunt in the one?
我們上個星期就試過了
We tried that last week.
真難搞
I don't know.
從策略上看 這樣應該能行
On paper, this should work.
只是能行還不夠好
Better than just work.
他們每個人都能以一敵百
You put them in singles against 100 other kids,
我敢說他們全都會名列前茅
I'd bet on that being the top eight finishers out there.
問題就在這
That's the problem.
他們總是以為
They have a hard time remembering
自己劃的是雙槳艇 尤其是蘭茨
they aren't in sculls, especially Rantz.
他們是我見過的最強大的賽艇隊
They're a strong a group as I've ever seen come through here
但他們可能也是我見過的最差勁的隊員
and they might also be the worst crew I've ever seen.
他們八字不合
It's a bad mix.
這是我一手造成的
It's my fault.
額 也許有問題的不是他們
Well, maybe those names aren't the problem.
有時候年紀小的馬需要嗓音更大的騎師
Sometimes young horses need a louder jockey.
你找我嗎 教練
You wanted to see me, Coach?
把門關上
Close the door.
坐吧
Sit down.
你知道我為什麼把你叫到這嗎
You know why I called you here?
我覺得你需要一個人幫你打敗加州大學
My guess is you need someone to help you beat Cal.
我們把話說清楚
Let me explain something to you.
我要給你第二次機會
I'm giving you a second chance.
你要去給青年隊當舵手
You're gonna drive the JV boat.
- 青年隊嗎 - 對 沒錯
- JV? - Yeah, that's right.
現在你聽好了
Now, listen to me.
你要對我言聽計從 說一不二
You're gonna do what I tell you, when I tell you.
如果我看見你擅離職守 你就給我走人
And if I see you goin' off on your own, then you're out.
這一次是來真的 你明白嗎
For good this time. You understand?
- 我明白 - 好
- Yeah, I do. - All right.
出去吧
Get out.
來吧
Come on!
你們的手抬得太高了
Your hands are too high!
修正提槳姿勢
Fix the catch.
同時提槳 來吧
One catch, let's go.
你們可是一支隊伍啊 夥計們
Look like a team, fellas.
蹬腿 抬頭
Legs through, eyes up.
蹬腿
Legs through.
你們節奏不協調 跟著休謨
You guys are out of sync. Find Hume.
以休謨為基準
Take it off Hume.
注意槳葉的高度
Watch those blade heights.
蘭茨 你聽著嗎 跟著休謨的節奏
Hey, Rantz, you with us? Get with Hume.
蹬腿
Legs through.
蹬腿 來呀
Legs through. Come on!
戴 你的槳提得太高了
Day, you're catching too high. Lower.
莫裏斯 你慢了
Morris, you're late.
好了 別劃了 別劃了
Enough! Way- nuff! Way- nuff!
劃得不錯
Yeah, good ride.
尤其是當你們各自不同入水的時候
And my favorite part is how my nuts vibrated
我的蛋蛋被震得欲僊欲死
when you guys were all hitting the water at different times.
速度雖然慢得像烏龜 但震感還挺不錯的
We were moving slow as shit, but the sensation was nice.
去你的 莫克
Screw you, Moch.
不 花花公子 去死的是你們
No, dandy, you're the one screwed.
教練告訴我
Coach told me if you guys
如果你們不調整好自己
don't get yourselves figured out,
你們不僅不能參加賽艇會
you're not only missing the regatta,
這一整年都不用比賽了
you're not racing at all this year.
你們拚死拚活
That's a whole hell of a lot of work
別到頭來竹籃打水一場空
to just do nothing with.
所以 想再來一次嗎
So, feel like trying it again?
我準備好了
I'm ready.
塗得很不錯
That's good.
一直順著紋路塗
Always with the grain.
你們賽艇隊進展如何
How's the crew coming along?
比我想像的難太多了
Lot harder than I expected.
工欲善其事 必先利其器
Well, that's what practice is for.
教練會讓你們做好準備的
Coaches will have you ready for the regatta.
你們會參加嗎
Your folks gonna make it?
我母親 我小的時候她就去世了
My mother, she passed when I was young.
我老爸 幾年前他為了找工作不得不搬出去
And my pop, he had to move off several years ago to find work.
算是斷了聯繫
Kinda lost touch.
那是誰把你養大的
Who brought you up?
我老爸認為我可以自力更生
Pop figured I was okay on my own.
嗯
Hmm.
那時候你多大
How old were you?
快14歲
Almost 14.
他和我的後媽
Him and my stepmom,
他們要照顧兩個小男孩
they had two young boys to care for.
史魁恩附近找不著工作
There was no work around Sequim.
這樣對大家都好
Worked out best for everybody.
蹬腿
Legs through.
蹬腿 肩膀放鬆
Legs through. Soften the shoulders.
抬頭
Eyes up.
保持放鬆
Stay loose.
喬 把肩膀放下
Shoulders down, Joe.
肩膀放低
Stay low.
保持放鬆
Stay loose.
抬頭
Eyes up.
好點了嗎
Better?
上下一心
As one.
用力踩踏板
Put the pressure in the footplate.
拉槳
Drive!
就是這艘艇 夥計們
Here she is, boys.
可能是喬治造過的最好的艇
Maybe the finest George has ever made.
現在 這就是你們新的歸屬
Now, this is your new home.
把她當做家
Treat her that way.
照顧她 保護她
Care for her. Protect her.
最重要的是 你們最好尊重她
Most of all, you better respect her.
好了 穿好衣服 出去吧
All right, suit up and get out there.
一周後你們和加州大學比賽
You race against Cal in a week.
我們不會讓你失望的 教練
Won't let you down, Coach.
今日的華盛頓湖畔風和日麗
Welcome to a beautiful day at Lake Washington
華盛頓哈士奇隊與伯克利的加州熊隊
for the annual showdown between the Washington Huskies
將在這裏展開他們在太平洋海岸帆艇賽的年度對決
and the Cal Bears of Berkeley in the Pacific Coast Regatta.
正如過去三十年以來一樣
And just as it has been for the past 30 years,
兩英里長的賽道將從沙角
the two- mile race will extend from Sand Point
延伸至謝裏登海灘
up to Sheridan Beach.
十萬名賽艇愛好者聚集於此
We have 100,000 race fans gathered here
期待一場自新奧爾良以來
for what is sure to be another maritime battle
前所未有的海上激戰
the likes of which we haven't seen since New Orleans.
華盛頓哈士奇的教練艾爾·烏爾布裏克森
And in the purple and gold, Washington Huskies coach,
身披紫金戰袍 帶領著一支強大的高級隊
Al Ulbrickson, is bringing back a strong senior team
和一支未經沙場的青年隊
and an inexperienced junior boat,
希望能夠扭轉去年的頹勢
in hopes of reversing a devastating season last year.
毫無疑問 他面臨著激烈的競爭
Without a doubt, he's facing stiff competition.
傳奇教練凱·埃布萊特再一次
Legendary Coach Ky Ebright has once again
帶來了兩艘強勁的賽艇
brought two strong boats.
他聲稱他的槳手
He's called his junior crew
活力四射 實力超凡
possibly the best young oarsmen he has ever had.
加油 華盛頓
Let's go, Washington!
嗨 羅傑
Hi, Roger.
別用力過猛了 聽莫克的指令
Don't try and do too much. Listen to Moch.
跟緊他們 希望加州隊出現失誤
Stay close, and we'll hope Cal makes a mistake.
身體放鬆
Stay calm with the body.
舉起你的手...
Hold your hands up...
- 振奮人心 - 是嗎
- Inspiring. - Hmm?
你是沒聽到我跟他們說
Uh, you missed the part where I told 'em
別翻艇就行
just to try not to tip over.
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
請大家入座
please take your seats.
比賽將在五分鐘後開始
Five minutes till the start.
嘿 艾爾 我的孩子
Hey, uh, my boys are feeling
身體有些不適
a little under the weather, Al.
希望你別對我們窮追猛打
I hope you take it easy on us.
即使我相信你也不會的 凱
Not even if I believed you, Ky.
兩支隊伍已就位
Both teams are in position.
風正從北方以每小時五英里的速度吹來
Winds are out of the north at five miles an hour.
華氏71度：大概21.67度
氣溫處於溫和的華氏71度
The temperature is a mild 71 degrees.
好了 各位 你們聽到烏爾布裏克森的話了
All right, boys. You heard Ulbrickson.
跟緊他們 並希望他們出現失誤
Stick close and hope they make a mistake.
他的潛台詞是別讓他下不來台
That's his way of saying don't embarrass him
因為他相信你們會的
'cause that's what he thinks you're gonna do.
要我說讓他見鬼去吧
I say the hell with all that.
這些人來這裏不是為了看你們甘落下風的
All these people didn't just come to see you stick close.
我們要讓烏爾布裏克森看看我們的厲害
Let's show Ulbrickson what's in this boat.
準備好了嗎
Ready?
二八年之魂
哈士奇快艇
槳手們已經準備就緒
The oarsmen are at the ready.
- 開劃 - 劃啊
- Row! - Row!
箭離弦了
And they're off!
華盛頓隊出發有些許遲緩
Washington is slow off the block.
早點把他們甩掉 38槳
Step on 'em early! 38!
衝啊 很好
Let's go! Good.
我們能行的
Yeah, we got 'em.
好了 保持簡單輕鬆的28槳
All right. Give me a nice, easy 28.
入水 破水
In and through.
拉槳
And pull!
華盛頓的青年隊
Washington's JV boat
是首次參加比賽
is racing for the first time in competition.
- 加州隊趕超了 - 小菜一碟
- Cal breaks early. - Easy work.
加州隊領先華盛頓隊半艘艇的距離
Cal has half a boat on Washington.
漂亮 夥計們 幹得漂亮
Easy, boys. Nice and easy.
加州隊一舉取得領先
Cal jumps out to an early lead.
華盛頓隊正在奮起直追
Washington is struggling to keep pace.
這就對了 別讓他們離開視線
That's right. Just keep them in sight.
槳葉不要抬得太高 麥克米林
Don't sky the blade, McMillin!
入水 破水
In, through.
肩膀放鬆
Shoulders loose.
腿用力
In the legs!
加州隊試圖與華盛頓隊拉開一條艇的距離
Cal opening up a full boat on Washington.
賽程的四分之一標記處 加州隊已經領先了一條艇的距離
And at the quarter mark, it's Cal up a full boat.
加油 加油啊 華盛頓
Come on! Come on, Washington!
我們可以的 各位 加油啊
We got this, boys! Come on.
破水
Through.
入水 破水
In, through.
保持鎮定 鮑比
Don't panic, Bobby.
別急
Don't rush.
加州隊沒有任何慢下來的跡象
Cal still showing no signs of slowing down.
華盛頓隊首次嘗到了比賽的滋味
Washington is getting its first taste of competition.
烏爾布裏克森教練可以從中吸取經驗
Something Coach Ulbrickson can hope to build on.
破水 入水 破水
Through! In, and through!
用力 用力
Push! Push!
諸位 時機已到
All right, here we go, boys.
給我35槳
Give me 35.
讓他們瞧瞧我們的厲害
Let's show 'em what we got.
前進 全速前進
Build! Build it!
他們是怎麼回事 我說了讓加州隊領先
What are they doing? I said let Cal come back to them.
比賽進行到了一半
Now at the halfway mark.
哈士奇隊猛然爆發
The Huskies with a burst.
半程標記處剛過 華盛頓隊便蓄勢待發
Just passing the halfway point and Washington is surging.
莫克 你最好心裏有數
Oh, you better be right, Moch.
入水 破水
In, through!
- 入水 破水 - 他們來了
- In, through! - Here they come.
華盛頓隊鉚足了勁
Here comes Washington.
抬頭
Eyes up.
- 抬頭 - 用力
- Eyes up! - Push!
他們經過了四分之三賽程標記點
They're past the three- quarter mark.
加州隊和華盛頓隊並駕齊驅
Cal and Washington are neck and neck!
- 加油 - 劃啊
- Go! - Row!
保持放鬆
Stay loose!
用力 用力
Push! Push!
加州隊在落人下風
Cal is falling back.
衝啊
Let's go!
華盛頓隊正加速前進
Washington is picking up the pace!
華盛頓趕超了加州隊
Washington's passing Cal!
瞧啊
And look at this.
華盛頓隊取得了領先
The Washington boat has taken the lead!
華盛頓隊領先半身艇
Washington by half a boat!
- 劃 衝啊 - 加油啊
- Row! Let's go! - Come on!
賽程僅剩兩百米
Two hundred meters to go!
- 華盛頓遙遙領先 - 再來二十槳
- Washington is pulling ahead! - Twenty more strokes!
快 快
Come on, come on.
加油 衝啊
Come on! Go!
華盛頓隊領先一艘艇的距離
Washington by a full boat!
- 入水 破水 - 一百米
- In and through! - One hundred meters!
再來十五槳
Fifteen more!
加油 加油
Come on! Come on!
破水 再來十槳
Through! Ten more!
五十米
Fifty meters!
華盛頓隊勝利在望
Washington is going to do it!
你們可以的 入水 破水
You got this! In and through!
用力
Push!
二十五米
Twenty- five meters!
終點近在眼前
And there's the flag!
華盛頓贏了
Washington has done it!
華盛頓青年隊贏下了他們的第一場比賽
Washington's junior boat has won their first competition!
多麼前程似錦的一群年輕人
What a promising start for these young men!
天吶
Jesus!
我的表比賽道記錄快了九秒
I got nine seconds under the course record.
一樣
Same.
最後的三分之一比一開始還要快
And the final third is faster than the first.
好一場天降奇兵
Where the hell did that come from?
我想那個小矮子自己心裏真有數
I guess that little runt knew what he was doin'.
你們都是海洋的
It's all you, boys!
所有人
All you!
一
One!
二
Two!
三
Three!
我喜歡你的帽子 謝謝 謝謝
I like your hat. Thank you. Thank you.
來吧
Come on!
華盛頓
Washington!
好樣的
Come on!
天啊
Oh, my God.
嗨
Hi.
我會習慣的
I could get used to this.
贏了第一場比賽感覺如何
How did your first win feel?
好極了
Great.
下一場我們會更快
Next one's gonna be even faster.
你們怎麼會劃得那麼快
How did you go so fast?
我們只是有多快劃多快
Oh, we just rowed as quick as we could.
那肯定十分艱難 即使你很強壯
It must have been hard, even though you're strong.
你累了嗎
You get tired?
有一點 比賽非常艱難
Yeah, yeah, it was pretty rough.
累到不能去某個安靜的地方
Too tired to go someplace quiet
給我看看你是怎麼做的嗎
and show me how you did it?
當然不
Oh, hell no.
你知道嗎 就算莫裏斯老是吐我背後
You know, this might make all the times
這一切也值了
Morris puked on my back worth it.
這是我今天得的
I got this today.
一個穿著西裝的傢伙給我的
Some fellow in a suit just gave it to me.
- 他說我們的勝利讓他開心極了 他想讓我... - 見鬼 我們都讓他開心 戈多
- Said us winning made him so happy, he wanted me to have... - Shoot, we all made him happy, Gordo.
我代數課上的同學
Kid in my algebra class
主動提出幫我完成作業
offered to do my homework for me.
- 我讓他們做了 - 你應得的
- I let the sap do it. - You should.
我們一直贏下去
We keep on winnin',
這裏的人會替我們完成作業的
we're gonna have it made in this place.
- 你今天表現真不錯 - 什麼
- You did so good today. - Huh?
我說你今天...
I said you did so...
我說你今天表現真不錯
I said you did so good today.
謝謝
Thank you.
還蠻有趣的
It was... It was fun.
什麼
What?
靠近點 我說蠻有趣的
Come here. I said it was fun.
你想去個安靜點的地方嗎
Do you wanna go someplace quiet?
我們在幹什麼呢
Watcha doin'?
我在旁觀
I'm watching.
你怎麼不找人說說話
Why aren't you talking to anybody?
我不太喜歡說話
I'm not much of a talker.
嘿 你看那邊
Hey, look over there.
看到那個戴眼鏡的瘦竹竿了嗎
You see that beanpole in the glasses?
看到了
Yeah.
他在學拉丁語
He's studying Latin.
- 哦 - 拉丁語
- Oh. - Latin.
你不需要說很多
You don't have to say much.
聽著 休謨
Listen, Hume.
今晚 不是明晚 也不是下周
Tonight, not tomorrow night, or next week.
今晚是你最佳的機會
Tonight is your best shot.
你去吧 我就算了
You go on. I think I'm okay.
天吶
Christ sake.
嘿 聽我說
Hey, listen up!
我們當中有一位音樂家
We got a musician in our midst.
若有你們的鼓勵
With a little encouragement,
他說不定會給我們現場演奏幾曲
we might just get him to give us some live music.
唐·休謨
Don Hume!
上來啊 快上來
Get up here. Get up here.
來嘛 唐
Come on, Don!
不要 不要
No. No.
- 嘿 小心 - 不 不 不
- Hey, watch out. - No, no, no, no, no.
鮑比 把凳子拿來
Bobby, get the stool.
鋼琴家
The piano man.
約翰 約翰 約翰 約翰
John, John, John, John, John, John, John, John.
- 不 不 不 - 準備好了
- No, no, no, no, no. - There we go.
一切都準備就緒 音樂大師
All ready for you there, maestro.
讓我們為唐鼓掌
Let's hear it for Don!
唐·休謨
Don Hume.
來吧 唐
Come on, Don!
我們知道你能行的
We know you can do it.
- 來吧 唐 - 來嘛 唐
- Come on, Don. - Come on, Donnie.
我覺得我不該在這
I don't think that I should be here.
他不能進來
He can't be in here.
閉嘴吧 卡羅琳
Oh, shut up, Carolyn.
我上周看到你在窗戶旁抽煙了
I saw you smoking at your window last week.
- 那裏真是太吵了 - 是啊
- It was too loud in there. - Yeah.
人們很開心 他們在慶祝
People are happy. They're having fun.
對啊 都是你們的功勞
Yeah, because of you.
好了 我要換衣服了
Okay, I'm changing.
轉過去
Eyes on the wall.
好
Right.
你知道你們會贏嗎
Did you know you were gonna win?
不知道 我的手臂都在發抖
No. My arms, they were shaking.
我很緊張
I was so nervous.
我們的歡呼聲響徹雲霄
We were all screaming so loud.
廣播裏說這是史上最快的速度
The radio said it was the fastest ever.
是啊 我們的教練也是這麼說的
Yeah, that's what Coach told us.
我敢說你每場比賽都能贏
I bet you win every race.
只是千萬不要驕傲自大
Just don't get all stuck- up and everything.
我只是留著以防再遇見你
I just kept that in case I ever ran into you again.
我得...
And had to, um...
證明你對我的感情是真實的
prove that you had that crush on me, like I said.
辛達斯小姐 把門打開
Miss Simdars, open this door.
你該走了
You... You should go.
你該走了 你得離開了
You should go. You need to go. You need to go.
辛達斯小姐 快開門
Miss Simdars, open this door right now, young lady.
如果你是在裏面藏了男人
If you have a male visitor in there,
後果自負
well, you know the consequences.
等一下
One minute!
- 怎麼了 - 這會太遠嗎
- What? - Is that too far?
- 不會 - 你可以走了
- No. - You're fine.
辛達斯小姐
Miss Simdars!
我們不是很開心嗎
Ain't we got fun?
稅務員愈漸逼近
Tax collector's getting closer
但我們仍然歡樂無窮
Still, we got fun
一切皆有可能
There's nothing surer
富人更富而窮人更窮
The rich get rich and the poor get poorer
與此同時 趁時光尚未消逝
In the meantime, in between time
去享樂吧
Ain't we got fun?
好樣的
Well done!
好耶
Okay! Yeah!
先生們女士們 唐·休謨敬上
Don Hume, ladies and gentlemen.
- 哈佛和耶魯 是嗎 - 嗯
- Harvard, Yale? - Mm- hmm.
他們創下的紀錄我們望塵莫及
Both have put up times we haven't gotten close to.
他們是天生的料
That's how it usually goes.
東部的孩子蹣跚學步時就已經在艇上了
Kids back East are in boats before they're in shoes.
上學只是為了多些技能傍身
Schools just have more talent to choose from.
那些你用金錢便能買到
That's what money buys you.
我們需要一個優勢 湯姆
We need an edge, Tom.
破水 入水 破水
Through. In and through.
入水 破水
In and through.
破水
And through!
抬頭
Eyes up!
入水 破水
In and through!
挺直身姿
Stand tall.
蹬腿
Legs through.
入水 破水
In and through.
蹬腿
Legs through.
入水 破水
In, through.
In and through.
蹬腿
Legs through.
停槳
Way- nuff!
其他人都越來越疲憊 他們卻越來越來勁
Everybody else tires and they just get stronger.
他們已經第三次打敗校隊了
That's the third time they beat the varsity squad.
下次再接再厲
Maybe next time.
我只是覺得風險有點大
I just think it's too big of a risk.
波基普西不僅事關今年的錦標賽
Poughkeepsie is more than just the championship this year.
更事關奧運會
It's for the Olympics.
我明白這場比賽的重要性
I know what the race means, Tom.
在重大比賽中經驗往往充當我們的方向標
Experience counts for something in big races.
校隊的一半艇員
Half those guys on varsity
去年在波基普西完成了比賽
competed at Poughkeepsie last year.
- 他們輸掉了 - 他們今年會更好
- And they lost. - They're better this year.
如果你不知道他們的年紀
If you didn't know their ages,
你不知道他們劃了多久的艇
you didn't know how long they've been rowing,
拋棄所有的舊有印象...
you're looking at both boats for the first time...
後院裏的一場計時賽算不上什麼
A time trial in the backyard does not count.
這兩場比賽不能同日而語
That is not the same thing as a race.
你看看他們的時間
Look at the competition times.
事情沒有這麼簡單
It's not that easy.
得了吧 你知道的
Come on, you know that.
沒錯 沒錯
Yes. Yes.
我是知道
Yes, I know.
你好像把校隊當成廢物一樣
You're acting like the varsity boat is scrappin'.
你知道那支隊伍也沒輸過一場比賽
You know that boat hasn't lost a race either.
就在不久之前
And it wasn't that long ago
你還僅僅是希望那支青年隊
you were just hopin' the JV boat
能夠成功到達終點不翻艇
was gonna make it to the finish line without sinking.
反觀現在 艾爾
Now, Al,
現在你要在他們身上孤注一擲
now you're talkin' about putting all our chips on 'em.
你認為校隊能在柏林贏得獎牌嗎
Do you think varsity could medal in Berlin?
這不關拿獎牌的事
We're not talkin' about a medal.
這事關拿到那裏的入場券
We're talkin' about a shot at gettin' there.
他們也可能失敗
If they got there?
我說不好
I don't know.
我們今年需要一次勝利 艾爾
We need a win this year, Al.
我們的頂頭上司 他們需要一次勝利
The people who pay us, they need a win.
你要派一群乳臭未乾的孩子去
You send a boat full of kids down there
而他們出差錯了
and they trip up,
你在這裏便任人宰割
you're sticking your neck way out there.
我和你都要成為眾矢之的
Makes it a real easy target. And mine, too.
我需要這份工作
I need this job.
你怎麼看 喬治
What do you think, George?
你做賽艇手時
When you were in a boat,
沒有人能敵得上你的技術
you rowed like no one else that's ever come through here.
我還記得看著你
I remember watching you,
尋思著我的艇上要是有八個
wondering how fast one of my shells could go
像你一樣的人 那該劃得有多快
if there were eight just like you in it.
那群孩子
That bunch of kids
也許是最接近這個想法的了
might be as close to that as I'll ever get.
如果我派他們去但他們沒準備好呢
And if I send them out there and they aren't ready?
那就如湯姆所說
Then it's like Tom said.
項上人頭不保
The axe will likely fall,
慘不忍睹
and fall hard.
你現在的口氣就像我妻子
Now you're starting to sound like my wife.
海桑爾是個睿智的女人
Well, Hazel's a smart woman.
我就當你是在誇我了
I'll take that as a compliment.
大家早上好
Good morning, everybody.
多謝
Thank you.
眾所周知 波基普西賽艇會
Now, as we all know, uh, the Poughkeepsie Regatta
一直都是這個賽季最重要的一場比賽
is always the most important race of the season.
今年更甚
This year, there's even more riding on it,
因為獲勝隊將獲得參加奧運會的名額
because the winner will qualify for an Olympic spot.
好
Yes!
也是這場比賽 讓華盛頓大學
It's also a race that the University of Washington
吃了近二十年的憋
has not won in almost two decades,
但是...但是...
but... but...
我相信今年
...we have a boat this year
有一艘艇能改變這一局面
that I believe could change all that.
這艘艇不僅能拿下波基普西的勝利
A boat that could not only win at Poughkeepsie,
更者
but
能夠在柏林奧運會上一爭高低
is strong enough to have a real shot in Berlin.
這艘艇...
And, uh...
就是我們的青年隊
that boat is our junior boat.
沒錯 就是這樣
Yeah, you heard me.
聽著 我知道這有違常理
Listen, I understand that that's unorthodox.
- 有違常理 這簡直是瘋了 - 我會竭盡所能...
- Unorthodox? It's insane. - I'm doing everything I can...
你不能這樣做
You can't do that.
...為我們的隊伍和華盛頓大學
...in the best interests of our team
謀取最佳的利益
and the University of Washington.
謝謝
Thank you.
你扯犢子呢
This is bullshit!
你失心瘋了嗎
Have you lost your mind?
你把那些為此辛苦訓練了四年
What about those boys who spent
的孩子置於何地
the last four years working for this?
- 我的工作是派出最強的隊伍到水上去 - 你的工作 你的工資都是我付的
- My job is to put the best boat in the water, Ben. - Your job? I pay for your job.
沒有了贊助 你以為
Without the boosters, where do you think
你的艇隊的錢是天上刮來的嗎
the money for your boats comes from, huh?
還有你那該死的工資
For your goddamn salary?
你能不能不要干預我的工作
How about you let me do my job?
我們平心靜氣
Let's just settle down
好好地談談 來吧
and talk about this calmly. Come on.
沒什麼好說的 傑
There's nothin' to talk about, Jay.
我的艇隊我做主
My team, my decision.
那它就不會再是你的艇隊了
Then it's not your team anymore.
我會確保開往波基普西的火車
I'll make sure your ass is fired
離開之前你就會被解雇
before the train leaves for Poughkeepsie.
- 本 我們不要這麼... - 好吧
- Ben, we're not gonna get... - All right.
博爾思和你一樣有能力
Bolles is just as capable as you.
甚至比你更強
Better even.
我會做出和艾爾一樣的選擇
I'd do the same as Al.
我希望你知道自己在幹什麼
I hope you know what you're doing.
本
Ben!
我知道嗎
Do I?
你當然知道
Sure you do.
真不敢相信你要參加奧運會了
I can't believe you're going to the Olympics.
我們還得先打敗其他學校的隊伍
We gotta beat those other schools first,
但教練說我們的機會不比別人差
but Coach says we have as good a shot as anybody.
到了紐約你可不能和其他的女孩調情
You can't flirt with any of those New York girls.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
馬上回來
Be back in a second.
喬
Joe?
在報紙上看到了你的照片
Saw your picture in the paper.
小哈利把它剪了下來
Harry Junior clipped it out.
你什麼時候從加州回來的
When did you get back from California?
有幾年了
Couple of years.
你知道的 那裏的情況也好不到哪裏去
You know, things weren't much better down there.
所以說你一直都在這裏
So, you've been here all that time?
就在前面不遠
Down the road a bit.
你打算告訴我嗎
Were you ever gonna tell me?
你自己就過得挺好的
You're doin' all right.
你離家時我才14歲
I was 14 when you left.
在你那個年紀我都已經征戰沙場了
I went to war when I was that age.
那麼 你想做什麼 喬
So, what do you wanna do, Joe?
回家嗎
Move home?
我可以有人幫我打打下手
I mean, I could use the help.
這樣吧 我每天付你一美元
Tell you what, I'll pay you a dollar a day
如果你沒丟掉砍樹的本領
if you still remember how to cut a tree.
還是說你願意繼續劃你的艇
Or maybe you'd rather just keep rowing your boat.
你沒有任何虧欠我的 喬
You don't owe me a thing, Joe.
我不虧欠你
I don't owe you.
你過得很好
You're doing just fine.
我會轉達你的問好
I'll pass on regards.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
這樣最好
Works out for the best.
但這不代表著就沒事了
Yeah, but that doesn't make it okay.
也許吧
Maybe.
我得走了
I gotta go.
你該在旭日東昇前
You should come get some sleep
進來補補覺
before the sun rises over that.
我馬上就進去
I'll be in there soon.
那番景色定賞心悅目
I sure love that view.
我知道
I know.
我只希望我能像過去一樣欣賞
I just wish I could enjoy it the way I used to.
你想不想
Why don't you
進來欣賞另一番景色
come see if there's another view you can enjoy?
好
Okay.
謝謝
Thank you.
我們會成為世界上最快的艇員
We're gonna be the fastest crew the world has ever seen.
一定要凱旋歸來啊 艾爾
Bring home the championship, Al!
- 把金牌帶回來 - 我們會盡力的
- And a gold medal! - We'll try.
天吶
Oh, boy.
我們是要拿冠軍的對吧
We might wanna try and win this thing, huh?
別有壓力
No pressure.
- 祝你好運 - 凱旋而歸 男孩們
- Good luck! - Bring it home, boys!
我會守在收音機旁的
I'll be listening on the radio.
如果他們採訪了你記得問好
Say hello if they interview you.
也許這是個恰當的時機告訴你
This might be a good time to tell you
我的心為你怦然而動 喬
that I'm in love with you, Joe.
- 全體乘客上車 - 好了 我得走了
- All aboard! - All right. I gotta go.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
她看著我呢
Yeah, she looked at me.
蘭茨
Rantz!
我沒錢了 誰給我一便士
I'm busted. Someone give me a penny.
算你走運 我可以讓你旁觀
Lucky, I'll let you watch.
嘿 喬 把你夾克給我
Hey, Joe, give me your jacket.
這樣我就能付一半的錢了
That'll get me halfway to ante.
喬 別走嘛
Joe, stick around.
嘿 別跑呀 流浪漢喬
Hey, don't run away, Hobo Joe.
他只是耍耍嘴皮子
He's playin'.
他是耍嘴皮子的
He's playin'. He's playin'.
他耍嘴皮子呢
He's playin'.
- 天吶 查克 - 我只是在開玩笑
- Jesus, Chuck. - Was just jokin'.
你的笑話一點都不好笑
Yeah, well, your jokes are lousy.
我沒有別的意思
I didn't mean anything by it.
事實上 幾年前我老爸破產了 所以...
Truth is, my old man went bust years ago, so...
伍爾沃斯：美國連鎖超市
我穿的新衣服都是伍爾沃斯順來的
Any new clothes I wear, I swipe from Woolworth's.
無所謂
Doesn't matter.
我只是說我們沒什麼兩樣
Just sayin' we're not different.
你我二人
You and me.
只不過你不是個小偷
Except you're not a thief.
一 停槳
One! Way- nuff!
槳放下
Drop it.
再來一次 節奏需要再快一點
Again! Need to get sharper.
快
Come on.
你們節奏不協調 跟著休謨
You guys are out of sync. Find Hume.
以休謨為基準
Take it off Hume.
有點團隊的樣 夥計們
Look like a team, fellas.
上下一心
As one.
你們的節奏亂了
You're out of sync.
好了 別劃了 停槳
Okay, no, no. Way- nuff.
- 我們從哪出發 - 喬 你的心思在這裏嗎
- Where are we off? - Hey, Joe, you with us?
- 我嗎 - 對 跟著唐的節奏
- Me? - Yeah, lock in on Don.
你胡說八道什麼呢 問題不在我
What are you talkin' about? I'm not the problem.
再來
Go again.
快
Come on.
入水 破水
In and through.
來 再劃三槳 就三槳
All right, give me three more. Three,
二
two,
一 停槳
one. Way- nuff!
這樣下去墊底是沒跑了
That'd get us a solid sixth.
他們只是還在適應新的水域
It's new water, they're still getting comfortable.
剛開始還快一點 他們這是越來越不適應
First times were faster. They're getting less comfortable.
什麼狀況
What is the matter?
他們還沒協調 我會調教他們的 教練
Not in tune yet. I'll get 'em there, Coach.
那就別等黃花菜都涼了 鮑比
Let's do it before the race, Bobby.
再來
Go again.
好了夥計們 左舷 後退
All right, fellas. Port side, back it down.
右舷 旋塞打開 準備好了嗎
Starboard, tap on. Ready?
可能是緊張了
Probably nervous.
他們只是孩子 艾爾
They're just kids, Al.
這就是為什麼每個人都認為
That's why everybody told me
我不該帶他們來
I was wrong for bringin' them.
我承受不起他們孩子氣的代價
I just can't afford for them to be kids.
今時不同往日
Not anymore.
- 看起來他們... - 我知道問題出在哪了
- It looks like they... - I know what's wrong.
靠過來
Bring it in.
前五百米你們如魚得水
You have 500 perfect meters.
後五百米 簡直就像
And then another five, where it looks like
有八艘艇在水上游
you're rowing eight different boats.
只是時機有點不對罷了
The timing's just a little off.
喬 你的腦子在哪神遊呢 小子
Joe, where is your head at, son?
- 在艇上 - 不 不在
- It's in the boat. - No, it's not.
你按自己的節奏劃
You're setting your own pace.
你的槳抬得比其他人高
Your catch is higher than the rest.
- 我試著... - 別插嘴
- I'm trying to... - Don't interrupt me.
你好像在劃一艘單人艇
You're rowing like you're in a single.
我們日復一日的訓練
We've been doing this too goddamn long to forget
不可能讓你忘記自己是在八人艇上
you're in an eight- man shell.
你是想留在這艘艇上
Now, do you wanna be in the boat
還是說我需要找人替代你
or am I'm gonna put someone else in your seat?
無所謂
I don't care.
科伊
Coy!
你來代替蘭茨
You're in Rantz's seat.
下來 你無所謂是吧 那就滾蛋
Get out. You don't care? Get out.
科伊 來啊 動作快點
Coy, come on, let's go.
看樣子你明天要去比賽了
Looks like you're racin' tomorrow.
現在 我們也許可以有點賽艇隊的樣子
Now, maybe we can row as a team.
你去和教練談談 告訴他你想歸隊
And just go talk to Coach, tell him you want back in.
我不會低聲下氣求他讓我歸隊的
I'm not beggin' him to give my place back.
- 我受夠了 - 你要去哪裏
- I'm done with that. - Where you gonna go?
你身上甚至沒有買火車票的錢
Ain't like you got money enough for a train ticket.
我會想到辦法的 車到山前必有路
I'll figure somethin' out. I always have.
難道你要在波基普西蝸居在一輛車裏嗎
Are you gonna live in a car in Poughkeepsie?
羅傑 喬 你們好啊
Hello, Roger. Hello, Joe.
我需要給哈士奇快艇再塗上一層漆
I need to put another coat on the Husky Clipper.
你可以給我打下手
I could use a hand.
我祖父會讓我給他造的艇殼上油
My grandfather would let me help oil the shells he built.
因為氣味的緣故很多時候我都心懷怨恨
Most hate it because of the smell.
鯨油的香味撲入鼻中 他的聲音便立刻在我耳邊響起
I catch the scent of whale oil and immediately hear his voice
告誡我 "不要停下來
telling me to, "Keep putting it on
"直到你可以在反光中看到自己的雀斑"
"until you can see your freckles in the reflection."
這樣我才知道這艘艇又好又滑
That's how I'd know it was good and slick.
它會如利刃一般劃破水面
So it would cut through the water like a knife blade.
不管你劃得有多快
How it didn't matter how fast someone rowed
若是艇下的水不以正確的方式
if the water didn't flow across the hull
流經船體 那也沒用
in the exact right way.
如果不達到完美的平衡
If the weight wasn't balanced just right.
每個部件各司其職
Every piece working with the other.
賽艇隊也是一樣的道理
It's the same with the crew.
兩者之間其實沒有什麼區別
So much that there's really no difference between the two.
他們共度的時光將彼此緊緊聯結在一起
They're connected by all the hours spent together.
汗水和痛苦
Sweat and pain
融入了它的紋理之中 變成了一艘充滿魔力的快艇
bleeds into the grain as they become one magical thing
在水上乘風破浪
that moves across the water
彷彿這就是它的命定之途
like it was born to be nowhere else.
我造過許多好艇 但最好的
I've built a lot of good boats, but the best ones,
最好的艇
the boats where
每個部位都嚴絲合縫
every part fits exactly as it should,
艇上的每個人
where every man
都信任彼此
trusts the one behind him,
這樣的艇絕不會在歲月更迭中磨滅
they are the boats people remember forever.
這艘艇便是如此
That's what this boat could be.
若是沒有人能見識到它風馳電掣的身姿
Be a shame for anyone to miss seeing how fast it could go
那也太可惜了
with all the right pieces.
喬 你父親放棄了你 他離你而去
Joe, your dad gave up on you. He quit on you.
你所學到的就只有放棄
All you know is quitting.
但在我看來你不是他
But it seems to me you're not him.
你是嗎
Or are you?
我在那邊等你
I'll, uh, see you over there.
喬 你有何貴幹
What can I do for you, Joe?
我想歸隊
I want my seat back.
為什麼
Why?
我在上面度過的分分秒秒
All that time I spent in it,
我們共同成就的輝績...
the work we all did together...
那艘艇...
That boat...
是我的唯一
it's all I got.
男孩們...
The boys and...
是我的全部
It's all I got.
我不能失去這些
I can't lose that.
我在最初的時候就跟你們說過
You know, one of the first things I said to you boys was
如果你不能堅持下來也沒什麼可羞恥的
there's no shame if your body can't hold up to this.
精神上也是如此
The same goes for the mind.
聽著 我知道要像相信自己一樣
Listen, I know it isn't easy to trust every other person
相信艇上的其他人並不容易
on that boat as much as you trust yourself.
但這不僅僅在於你
But it's not about you.
儘管你很優秀 但這不在於你個人 喬
As good as you are, it's not about you, Joe,
不在於我 不在於任何人
or me, or anybody else.
艇才是最重要的
It's about the boat.
我知道了
Yes, sir.
那就是我心之所向
It's where I wanna be.
好吧
Okay.
那你最好換好衣服
Well, you better get dressed.
謝謝
Thank you.
真心感謝
Really, thank you.
今日的賽艇會
Today's regatta
既是一場比賽 也是一場社會實驗
is as much a social experiment as it is a race.
階層的衝突
A clash of character.
資產階級與無產階級的對立
Of old money versus no money at all.
其他六支艇隊尋求榮譽 而剩下一支艇隊力求魚死網破
Six boats of want- to's against one filled with have- to's.
這九個工人階級的男孩來自美國西部
These nine working- class boys arrived from the American West
他們肩負著一個國家的重任
on the shoulders of a country that sees itself
在他們稚嫩的臉龐上唯有堅定不移的決心
in their determined young faces.
他們的掙扎 他們的勇氣 他們的精神顯露無遺
Sees their struggles, their grit, their spirit.
他們哈士奇視為自身
And they've claimed the Husky Clipper as their own.
因為這艘艇滿載著弱者
Because it's a boat full of underdogs
代表著孱弱的國家
representing an underdog nation.
這個國家的人民飽受欺凌
A nation of people who have been beaten down
卻仍堅守著自己的國土
but refuse to go away.
堅持努力工作 因為這是他們心之所想
Refuse to stop working hard, 'cause that's all they know.
亙古至今
All they have ever done.
那麼請落座 不管你是在河邊還是在收音機旁
So, find your place, by the river or the radio.
為勇氣、信心和力量歡呼喝彩
And cheer for guts and heart and brawn
他們將在今天的終點線擊敗特權與名望
to beat privilege and prestige to the finish line today.
為來自華盛頓的男孩們歡呼喝彩
Cheer for the boys from Washington.
聽好了 我們在第七道
Listen up. We're in lane seven.
海軍隊和加州隊會試圖取得領先
Navy and Cal are gonna wanna jump to a lead.
任他們去吧
We just let 'em.
成敗在此一舉 孩子們
This is it, boys.
強勢有力的開局
Nice, strong start.
我們保持42槳的速度 好嗎
We're gonna keep a 42 count coming out, right?
加州隊會使出全部力氣 好嗎
California's gonna go out hard, okay?
你們得跟緊他們
You gotta stick with them.
只要你們位於兩米的範圍之內
As long as you're within two lengths,
- 保持30槳就行 - 你的肩膀怎麼樣了
- stay under a 30 stroke. - How's your shoulder?
- 你還好嗎 - 我沒事
- Are you okay? - I'm good.
我希望你們挺過那股痛苦
I wanna see you push yourself through that pain.
然後在半程標記點提到35
Then go to a 35 at the halfway mark.
你們要慢下來 慢慢地進入平穩的34槳
You're gonna slow down and ease into a nice, steady 34.
不斷前進 持之以恆
Keep going, keep pushing.
不達終點不罷休
Keep pushing all the way through.
前面的艇感到疲憊之時 你們便可後來者居上
All the boats out in front will start to tire and you'll just be getting started.
你們知道計劃的
You know the plan.
剩下的我們結束再說
We'll save something for the end.
區區四英里的賽程對你們來說易如反掌
Four miles in a boat should be nothing to you.
你們主宰著這場比賽 好嗎
This is your race, all right?
去大展拳腳吧
This is our time.
我們知道自己在做什麼 大家都是過來人了
We know what we're doin'. We've been here before, boys.
是時候大幹一場 讓他們見識我們的實力了
Now better get out there and show 'em what I already know.
波基普西賽艇會
The Poughkeepsie Regatta.
今日的賽事
Today's regatta is the greatest
是美國有史以來最盛大的一次
one- day rowing event in America.
- 注意腳下 - 像凱·埃布萊特
- Watch your step. - Coaches like Ky Ebright,
羅斯蒂·卡洛和艾爾·烏爾布裏克森這樣的教練
Rusty Callow and Al Ulbrickson
不僅希望獲勝
are not only hoping for a win,
更是在尋求通往柏林奧運會的入場票
but a chance to compete in Berlin.
正當賽艇愛好者登上觀賽車
As rowing fans board observation cars
聚集在哈德遜河岸邊之際
and crowd the shores of the Hudson River,
七艘艇已經停靠在起點線上
seven shells take their places at the starting line.
錫拉丘茲隊 海軍隊
Syracuse, Navy,
康奈爾大學隊 哥倫比亞大學隊
Cornell, and Columbia,
賓夕法尼亞大學隊 加州大學隊以及華盛頓大學隊
Penn, Cal, and Washington ready themselves
為這場可能是他們人生中最重要的一場比賽
for what could be the most important race
做著最後的準備
of their young lives.
一個在奧運會大顯身手的機會
A chance to compete in the Olympics.
出發吧
Let's go.
- 祝你好運 傑克 - 也祝你好運
- Good luck, Jack. - You, too.
裁判舉起了發令槍
The starting gun is up.
槳在前方就位
Oars to frontstops.
近十萬名觀眾屏息以待
Nearly 100,000 spectators hold their breath in anticipation.
一片寂靜籠罩著克魯姆灣
A hush falling over Crum Elbow.
- 劃 - 比賽開始
- Row! - And here we go.
華盛頓哈士奇隊此刻正與
Washington Huskies are now rowing
加州大學的高級隊較勁
against the seniors of Cal.
哈士奇隊是賽場上唯一的一支青年隊
Huskies are the only junior boat in the competition.
給我一個簡單明瞭的28槳
Give me a nice, easy 28.
緊跟唐的節奏
Fall in with Don.
入水 破水
In and through.
這七支訓練有素的隊伍
These seven finely trained crews
他們翻騰著哈德遜河上游的河水
are churning the waters of the Upper Hudson
在這場超凡的競賽裏
in a supreme rowing test
考驗著他們的力量、速度和身體協調性
of power, speed and coordination.
保持這個節奏 鮑比
Hold that pace, Bobby.
在四分之一標記點處 加州隊 賓州隊
And at the quarter mark, we have California, Penn
以及海軍隊
and Navy out in front
以半條艇的距離處於領先地位
with a half- boat lead on the rest of the field.
好樣的 你們的槳頻非常好
All right, your stroke rate is perfect.
節省你們的體力
Save your power.
讓他們疲憊去吧
Let 'em get tired.
磨掉他們的體力
Wear 'em down.
華盛頓隊正跌回最後一名的位置
Washington is falling back to last place.
落後四米
Four lengths behind the leaders.
就是現在 鮑比
Now, Bobby.
蓄力
Save!
蓄存體力
Save power.
消耗他們的體力
Wear 'em down.
- 他在幹什麼 - 機不可失時不再來呀
- What's he doing? - It has to be now.
加油啊 孩子們
Come on, boys.
待命
Wait for it.
好了 唐 給我36槳 來吧
All right, Don, give me 36. Go!
蹬腿
Legs through.
他們發力了
And here they come.
為了尋找反攻優勢
Looking for freshwater,
鮑比·莫克正駛入錫拉丘茲的航道
Bobby Moch is steering right into Syracuse's lane.
- 入水 破水 - 衝啊
- In and through. - Let's go.
抬腿
Legs up.
戳啊戳
Jab! Jab!
離我們遠點
Get off us!
見鬼去吧 錫拉丘茲隊
Hey, go to hell, Syracuse!
你在發什麼神經
What the hell is that?
華盛頓隊把錫拉丘茲隊甩在了身後
Washington is passing Syracuse.
他們的身後還有一英里半的距離
And with a mile and a half behind them,
各隊逐漸落後
teams are falling away
但沒人能趕得上加州隊和海軍隊
but no one is gaining on California and Navy.
好樣的
Attaboy.
劃 劃
Row! Row!
保持著兩艇長的領先優勢
Holding a four- length lead,
加州隊和海軍隊如入無人之境
Cal and Navy are in a two- boat race.
好了 為了烏爾布裏克森 用力地劃上十槳 衝啊
All right, give me 10 big ones for Ulbrickson. Go!
華盛頓隊奮起直追
Washington has picked up the pace.
鮑比·莫克終於讓他的艇員醒悟過來回到比賽中
Bobby Moch finally getting his crew in this race.
哈士奇隊將康奈爾隊遠遠甩在身後
The Huskies sweeping by Cornell.
直逼賓州隊和哥倫比亞隊
Headed for Penn and Columbia.
海軍隊與加州隊仍然領先四個艇的距離
Navy and Cal still ahead by four lengths.
好了 給我四十槳
All right! Give me 40!
衝啊
Let's go!
入水 破水
In, through!
華盛頓隊迅速趕上了哥倫比亞的雄獅隊
Washington is quickly gaining on Columbia's Lions.
最好別太遲了
Better not be too late.
哈士奇快艇緊逼哥倫比亞隊...
The Husky Clipper bustles by Columbia...
- 用力 - ...來到了第三名的位置
- Come on! - ...and into third place!
使勁
Come on!
推進 伸展
Push! Extend!
就是現在 再劃十槳
Now, give me 10 more
為了波科克
for Pocock!
剩餘四百米 華盛頓隊勢如破竹
With 400 meters to go, here comes Washington!
入水 破水
In and through!
In, through!
- 破水 - 再劃二十槳
- Through! - Twenty more strokes!
十九
Nineteen!
華盛頓隊已經來到了第二名的位置
Washington has taken second place!
他們是否還有足夠的體力追趕加州隊呢
Do they have enough left to catch Cal?
蹬腿
Legs through!
- 前進吧 孩子們 - 加油啊
- Come on, boys. - Come on.
你們能行的 孩子們
You got this, boys.
看華盛頓隊吶
Look at Washington!
這個場景簡直如夢似幻
I don't believe what I'm seeing.
哈士奇隊能做到嗎 他們能成功嗎
Can the Huskies do it? Can they do it?
給我有力的十槳
Give me 10 big ones
讓那些不相信你們的人看看你們的實力
for all the people who didn't believe in you!
衝啊
Go!
拿下加州隊
Give me Cal!
我要拿下加州隊
I want Cal!
對 這樣就對了 蕪湖
Yeah, we're workin'! Whoo!
他們要出擊了
They're making their move!
孩子們 加油
Boys, come on.
蹬腿
Legs through!
最後還剩兩百米
With 200 meters left,
華盛頓隊正在趕超加州隊
Washington is passing Cal!
入水 破水
In, through!
抬頭
Eyes up!
最後一百米 華盛頓隊勝利在望
With 100 meters to go, Washington is going to do it!
華盛頓要到達終點了
Washington is going to do it!
破水 入水 破水
Through! In and through!
- 抬頭 入水 - 快啊
- Eyes up! In! - Come on.
華盛頓隊贏得了比賽 觀眾朋友們
Washington has won the race, folks!
華盛頓隊贏得了比賽
Washington has won the race!
華盛頓隊贏了
Washington has won!
多麼動人心魄的一場比賽
What a race!
烏爾布裏克森教練的孤注一擲得到善果
Coach Ulbrickson's big gamble has paid off,
女士們先生們
ladies and gentlemen.
華盛頓哈士奇隊
The Washington Huskies
將赴柏林爭奪金牌
are going to Berlin to compete for gold.
- 好一場酣暢淋漓的比賽 - 太好了
- What a race indeed! - Yes!
哦...
Oh...
我喜歡你的笑容
I do love your smile.
你應該多笑笑
You should do it more often.
我們做到了 兄弟們
We did it, boys!
我覺得你是要害我們都患上心臟病
I think that you were trying to give us all a heart attack.
不到萬不得已我不想打亂他們的節奏
I just didn't want to break their rhythm till I had to.
我真的不知道
I honest to God didn't know
世界上有那麼多的蝦
there were this many shrimp in the entire world.
你是否能與我們的聽眾分享一二
Do you mind sharing with our listeners,
當你們落後四個艇長時你在艇上有何感想
what was the feeling in the boat when you were four lengths back?
你們驚慌了嗎
Was there any panic?
沒人驚慌
Uh, there was no panic.
我們全都鎮定自若
All of us,
我們知道必要的時候我們可以將劣勢彌補回來
we knew we could make up the ground when we needed to.
如果可以的話
And, if I could,
我想向我的喬伊斯打個招呼
could I say hello to my girl Joyce back home?
待我衣錦還鄉之時 我會讓你戴上金牌
I'll let you wear the gold medal when I get back.
沒錯 聽眾朋友
That's right, folks.
他們會替華盛頓的所有人
They'll be bringing the gold medal home
把金牌帶回家
for all of us back in Washington.
這真不錯
This is great.
所以你們早就知道的情況
So, you guys all knew about it when?
我卻今晚才知情
And I'm hearing about it tonight?
你知道這在我看來像什麼嗎
You know what this sounds like to me?
看上去像是你們改變了規則
It sounds like you guys are changing the rules
好竊取屬於我們的榮譽
because you're trying to steal this from us.
沒人要竊取任何東西 烏爾布裏克森教練
No one is trying to steal anything, Coach Ulbrickson.
我現在是以
I'm just speaking to you
美國賽艇奧委會主席的身份
as the U.S. Rowing Olympic Chairman
與你談話
and telling you the facts.
美國艇協沒有資金
U.S. Rowing does not have the money
資助你們的柏林之旅
to fund your trip to Berlin.
這怎麼可能
And how is that even possible?
不僅僅是賽艇
It's not just rowing.
游泳 擊劍
Swimming, fencing.
還有許多其他運動項目都面臨著...
There are many other sports that are dealing with...
我們到底該拿出多少錢
Exactly how much are we supposed to come up with?
- 五千美元 - 五千
- $5,000. - Five?
- 一周內 - 一周內
- In a week? - In a week.
如果我們拿不出來呢
And what if we can't come up with it?
委員會只好另尋
Well, the committee would have to find
一支合適的替代隊伍參加柏林奧運會
a suitable replacement to compete in Berlin.
誰合適呢 亨利 你的賓州隊嗎
Suitable like who, Henry? Like your Penn squad?
如果有必要的話
If necessary, yes.
我們當然會優先考慮加州隊
We'd of course give California the first opportunity.
無論哪支隊總好過
Either team is a better option
缺席奧運會
than not sending a team at all.
你在扯淡 亨利 都是廢話
This is bullshit, Henry. It's bullshit.
你沒想到我們會贏 但我們贏了
You didn't expect us to win, and we won.
對 你們在水上都失敗了 每一個人
Yeah, you couldn't win on the water. None of you.
眼下情況非我所願
I don't like this situation.
你現在是在編造規則 胡說八道
Now, you're makin' up the rules. Bullshit.
我也和你一樣
I don't like the situation
- 不願看到這樣的情況 - 你就扯吧
- any more than you do. - Yeah, sure you don't.
- 扯淡 - 我們會想出辦法的
- Bullshit. - We'll figure this out.
我們到底該怎麼拿出五千美元
How are we supposed to come up with $5,000?
我們的大學會聯繫校友和支持者
Our university will reach out to alumni and boosters.
看看他們能不能出力
See if they can scrape anything up.
如果他們找不到足夠的錢呢
And if they can't find enough?
那機會就會給加州隊
Then it'd be Cal
或賓州隊
or Penn.
他們都是我們的手下敗將
We beat those guys.
我知道
I know.
我們決不能讓那些紈褲子弟奪走我們的機會
No way we let those rich pricks go instead of us.
那我們最好湊點錢出來
Then we better find some money.
艾爾 你要去哪
Al, where you goin'?
幫我們趕赴柏林
Help us get to Berlin.
幫助哈士奇隊前往柏林
Help send the Huskies to Berlin.
多謝 祝你今天愉快
Thank you. You have a nice day.
- 多謝 先生 - 不客氣
- Thank you, sir. - Sure.
嘿 各位
Hey, guys.
奧運賽艇隊需要你的幫助前往柏林 我們只剩下幾天時間了
The Olympic rowing team needs your help to get to Berlin. We only got a couple days left.
夥計們 有人給了我一美元
Fellas, I got a dollar.
省下幾美元 幫助我們打敗德國人
Spare a couple dollars. Help us beat the Germans.
好了
All right.
謝謝 我是羅傑
Thanks. My name's Roger.
嘿 我是查克
Hey, I'm Chuck.
哦 得了吧
Oh, please.
教練 你們的時間不多了
Well, you're running out of days, Coach.
- 僅剩四天時間還是... - 三天
- You have what, four left? - Three.
我們所籌到的資金
And we've only gotten halfway
僅僅是奧委會說我們需要的一半
to what the Olympic Committee says we need.
那麼 如果你沒籌集到足夠的錢
So, if you don't raise the money,
你們便得打道回府去西雅圖
you go back to Seattle
而其他隊伍卻奔赴柏林
while some other team goes to Berlin?
沒錯 這違背了運動
Correct. And that goes against
的一切初衷
everything sports should be about.
運動員取得成績就應該受到獎賞
Athletes should be rewarded for performance.
不以政治論
No politics,
不暗箱操作
no adjusted scoring or selection
不受財富和聲望影響
based on wealth and standing.
狹路相逢優者勝
May the best man win.
這是他們的肺腑之言 事情本就該這樣
That's what they say. That's what it should be.
這些孩子 華盛頓的孩子們
These boys, Washington's boys,
這個國家的孩子們
this country's boys,
我的孩子們
my boys,
他們已經自證為佼佼者
they have proven themselves to be the best.
幫助我們哈士奇隊奔赴柏林
Help us send the Huskies to Berlin.
提醒一下各位 每一滴幫助都將匯成湖海
A reminder, folks, every little bit helps.
非常感謝
Thank you so much.
來吧 支持我們的孩子
Come on, support our boys.
好的 非常感謝
All right. Thank you so much.
感激不盡
Thank you so much.
非常感謝 謝謝
Thank you so much. Thank you.
塔科馬給了我們92美元以紀念羅傑·莫裏斯之名
We got $92 from Tacoma in honor of Roger Morris.
史魁恩為蘭茨給了我們75美元
$75 more from Sequim for Joe Rantz.
還有奧林匹亞給唐·休謨的90沒有
$90 from Olympia for Don Hume.
每一個孩子的家鄉都伸出了援手
Every hometown of these boys has given somethin'.
《太平洋電報》今晚剛剛送來了250沒有
Pacific Telegraph just sent $250 this evening.
算上那筆錢
Where does that put us
我們總共籌集了多少
with everything else we've got?
- 差不多了 - 但是呢
- Eh, close. - But?
差不多就是差不多 艾爾
Well, close is just close, Al.
我們時間不多了
And we're out of time.
烏爾布裏克森女士 我在找你丈夫
Mrs. Ulbrickson, I'm looking for your husband.
我們還有四個小時 凱
We still got four hours, Ky.
還是像往常一樣爭分奪秒
Racing the clock as usual.
我得跟你說實話 艾爾
I can't lie to you, Al.
奔赴柏林 我的孩子們求之不得
My boys would love to go to Berlin.
你還缺多少
How short are you?
300美元
$300.
粗略估計
Give or take.
我可以嗎
May I?
這是來自加州熊隊的
This is from the Cal Bears.
一張300美元的借條
An IOU for $300.
或多或少
Give or take.
凱
Ky.
沒有人你的孩子們更有資格
No one deserves to go but your boys.
先生們
Gentlemen.
烏爾布裏克森太太
Mrs. Ulbrickson.
如果錢還有餘 你可以給我帶點紀念品回來
And if there's any extra, you can bring me back a souvenir.
在曼哈頓號上
Aboard the SS Manhattan,
這艘滿載著美國運動員的船駛向漢堡
a shipload of American athletes sails for Hamburg.
他們以奧運會為自己的目標
The Olympic Games, their goal.
這是傑西·歐文斯
Here is Jesse Owens,
來自俄亥俄大學的一人田徑隊
the one- man track team from the University of Ohio.
有些人稱他為"史上最偉大的"
Some say, "The greatest ever."
300多名運動員將踏上
More than 300 athletes will march ashore
德國的國土 準備為金牌而戰
on German soil, ready to fight for gold.
這其中就包括了華盛頓大學的
Among the participants are the University of Washington's
八人賽艇青年隊
junior varsity eight- man rowing crew.
這支艇隊已經摩拳擦掌
The boat is ready to do battle
準備與諸如意大利、大不列顛
with the likes of Italy, Great Britain
德國等隊
and Germany,
在這場艱苦卓絕的比賽中一決雌雄
all favorites in this most grueling of events.
在柏林 奧運會的準備工作已經完成
In Berlin, the preparations for the Games are complete,
德國人民已經準備好歡迎
and the German people are ready to welcome
來自52個國家的運動員
athletes from 52 countries.
德國總理阿道夫·希特勒
German Chancellor Adolf Hitler
承諾過舉辦一場空前絕後的盛會
has promised a spectacle like no other,
並有意參與多項賽事
and plans to attend a variety of events.
在漢堡 成千上萬歡呼雀躍的德國人
In Hamburg, thousands of cheering Germans
歡迎準備下船的美國人
welcome the Americans as they ready to disembark.
這些業餘運動員
These amateur athletes
為了代表他們的國家付出了巨大的犧牲
have sacrificed so much to represent their country,
奧運會開幕式將在幾天後舉行
and as the opening of the Games is just days away,
海內外的美國人
Americans at home and abroad
期待為這些敬業的運動員加油助威
look forward to rooting for these dedicated athletes.
你好
Hi.
好的
All right.
換好衣服 我們去看看賽場
Get changed, we'll go look over the course.
這太棒了
This is great.
還不錯嘛
Not bad.
- 這樣就行了 - 比家裏好多了
- This'll do. - It's better than back home.
希特勒萬歲
Heil Hitler.
指阿拉莫之戰，這場戰役一度成為美國精神的代名詞，被美國人認為是自由意志下勇氣與犧牲精神的象徵，故以此回應"希特勒萬歲"
銘記阿拉莫
Remember the Alamo.
喬 開幕式要開始了
Joe, opening ceremony.
快走 你們要遲到了
Come on, you're gonna be late.
我想我就不去了
I think I gotta skip.
我太累了
I'm just too tired.
怎麼了 出什麼事了 唐
Why, what's the problem, Don?
唐感覺不太好
Don doesn't feel so great.
你去加入其他人吧 我留下來
Go join the rest. I'll, uh... I'll stay.
我留下來吧 你得伴著你的隊伍走出去
I'll hang back. You need to walk with your team.
謝了 喬治
Thanks, George.
好了 好好休息
All right, get some rest.
試著吃點東西
Try and eat somethin'.
匈牙利
Ungarn.
你是傑西對嗎 傑西·歐文斯
You're Jesse, right? Jesse Owens?
是的
I am.
你真的是世界上跑得最快的人嗎
You really the fastest man in the world?
- 我哪知道 - 這裏的人說
- I don't know. - Folks around here say
你會贏下每一場比賽
you're gonna win every race you're in.
希望如此
Well, I hope so.
讓那些德國人見識見識 好嗎
Show those Germans what for, all right?
- 不 - 不嗎
- No. - No?
與德國人無關
Not the Germans.
是為了我家鄉的父老鄉親
The folks back home.
美利堅合眾國
United States of America.
匈牙利隊
The Hungarian team
向德國總理致上他們的敬意
offering their respect to the German leader.
美國隊出場率
And here come the Americans.
美國隊沒有敬禮
With no salute from the United States.
聽起來你的隊友正廣交朋友呢
Sounds like the boys are making friends.
好了 起風了
All right, the winds are up.
這對我們有益 你們在第二道不受影響
That's good for us. You're protected in lane two.
讓更遠處的艇
Let all the other boats farther out
去應付強風吹拂吧
deal with the gusts.
鮑比 你越是堅守我們的航道
Bobby, the tighter you hold the line,
就能劃得更平穩
the smoother the ride.
現在是三場預賽
Now, three prelims.
每場的獲勝隊自動獲得進入決賽的資格
The winner of each gets an automatic berth in the finals.
這正合你們心意 休息一天
That is what you want. You want a day off
讓其他隊因為額外的比賽
and let the other teams wear themselves out
把自己累壞
with an extra race.
所以不要保留
So, do not hold back.
預選賽中的英國隊值得我們關注
Great Britain's the team to watch in our heat.
鮑比 不要重演波基普西的比賽
Bobby, not another Poughkeepsie.
他們不會像加州隊一樣後期乏力
They won't fade like Cal,
所以別讓他們拉開兩支艇的距離
so never let them get more than two lengths up.
夥計們 這是你們應得的
Fellas, you've earned this.
他們不會因個性拔群而頒發金牌
They don't give gold medals for style.
最重要的是水上的速度
All that matters is how fast you are on the water.
這裏無人能出你們之右
And nobody here is faster.
蹬腿
Legs through!
美國隊已然領先英國隊
And the Americans are already leading
半隻艇的距離
by half a boat over Great Britain
差距仍在拉大
and looking for more.
緊隨其後的是法國隊和捷克斯洛伐克隊
Followed by France and Czechoslovakia.
入水 破水 入水 破水
In, through! In, through!
領槳手蘭·勞力
Stroke Ran Laurie
正為英國隊挖掘更多的速度
is digging furiously for the British boat.
但美國隊
But the Americans
現在正全速前進 擴大他們的優勢
are pouring it on now, extending their lead.
抬頭 入水 破水
Eyes up. In, through!
破水
And through!
最後一百米
And with only 100 meters to go,
美國隊的成績直逼奧運會紀錄
the Americans could be closing in on an Olympic record.
抬頭
Eyes up!
六分鐘八秒
Six minutes point eight seconds.
新的奧運會紀錄誕生了
A new Olympic record!
美國隊拿下了比賽
The United States has won!
你還好嗎 你知道我們贏了嗎
You all right? Hey, you know we won?
- 唐 你沒事吧 - 你知道我們贏了吧
- Don, are you okay? - You know we won, right? Huh?
- 嘿 - 來嘛 來嘛
- Hey. - Come on. Come on.
精彩的比賽
Good race.
奧運會紀錄是個不錯的開局
Olympic record's a nice start.
但這一切只是為更重要的比賽打好基礎
But all that does is get us into the race that matters.
沒人會記得你們在預選賽創下了紀錄
Nobody is gonna remember you set a record at a preliminary.
現在...
Now...
去看看我們的對手吧
let's go see what we're up against.
好樣的
Good job.
幹得好 幹得漂亮
Way to go. Way to go.
好樣的 兄弟們
Good work, boys.
單人賽 雙人賽
Singles, doubles,
還有四人賽 他們屢戰屢勝
fours, they haven't lost a race yet.
很快
Fast.
唐 走吧
Don, come on.
嘿 走吧
Hey, come on.
你還好嗎
You all right?
教練 教練
Coach! Coach!
- 你沒事吧 - 沒事 我只是累壞了
- You okay? - Mm- hmm. I'm just worn out.
謝謝醫生 多謝你的幫助
Thank you, Doctor. Thanks for your help.
醫生怎麼說的
What's the word?
感染了某種蟲子 他們也不確定
Some kind of bug. They're not sure what.
現在 他脫水很嚴重
Right now, he's very dehydrated.
他需要休息
He needs rest.
你們在接下來的24小時裏離他遠點
And y'all stay away from him for the next 24 hours.
我們不能再失去任何一個人了
We can't afford losing anybody else.
失去是什麼意思
What do you mean, "losing"?
如果兩天後他的情況仍不見好轉 他不會參賽
If he's still like this in two days, he's not racing.
決賽航道分配
Lane assignments for the finals.
你不能在比賽中途
You can't change the rules
修改比賽規則
in the middle of a competition!
最快的隊伍有權優先選擇航道
The fastest qualifiers earn the favored lanes.
一直以來都是這樣
That is the way it's always been.
我們創下了最快的紀錄
And we posted the best time,
你卻給我玩消失 把我們困在外面
and you've gone and stuck us on the outside.
這是委員會決定的航道分配方案
This was the lane formula the committee decided on.
什麼時候 在你的賽艇隊
、When? Right after your squad
創下最慢紀錄的時候嗎
posted the slowest qualifying time?
你最好謹言慎行 烏爾布裏克森教練
Be careful of your accusations, Coach Ulbrickson.
你見到了賽場上的風況
You've seen the winds on that course and you know
你知道風起時能獲得兩艘艇的距離優勢
there's a two- length disadvantage when it blows.
我相信你的艇員能應付得來
I'm sure your crew will manage.
天氣預報員預計今天會風平浪靜
The forecasters expect a calm day.
好吧...
Well...
我們會提出抗議
We'll protest this.
我記下了 祝你好運
Noted. And good luck.
好了 聽好了 孩子們
All right. Listen up, boys.
這條航道不容樂觀 所以你們得先發制人
It's a tough lane, so you gotta start quick.
你們不能讓其他隊離開視線
You gotta keep them in sight.
最後五百米不受風的影響
That wind will be blocked for the last 500 meters.
那就是你們的機會
And that's your shot.
你們將在那裏一招制勝
That's where you're gonna take 'em,
但前提是你們不能讓他們離開視線範圍內
but only if you keep 'em in sight.
聽著 場上的每一支隊伍
Listen, every one of those teams
畢生都在為此刻而準備
have trained their whole lives for this moment.
他們都有著萬貫家財
They're all legacies.
但我們沒有
We're not.
為了你的國家
Row for your country.
為了彼此
Row for each other.
為了破釜沉舟
Row for that one moment when everything
撥開雲霧見天明的那一刻
that's stacked against you can take a back seat.
不管怎樣 我為你們感到驕傲
For what it's worth, I'm proud of you boys.
好了 啟航吧
All right, push off.
怎麼
What?
沒什麼
Nothin'.
他們還不如把我們扔到
They might as well have stuck us
北太平洋去呢
out on the North Atlantic.
數以千計的人們正在落座
Thousands of people are taking their seats,
觀看八人賽艇的決賽
gathered for the Men's Eights finals.
世界上最優秀的六支賽艇隊
The world's six best rowing teams
在最後一場比賽中角逐金牌
in one last race for the gold.
德國隊 意大利隊 匈牙利隊
Germany, Italy, Hungary.
德國隊已經在單人賽、雙人賽和四人賽中摘得金牌
Germany has taken gold in singles, doubles, and fours,
他們正朝著大滿貫努力
and they're looking for a sweep.
瑞士隊、大不列顛隊和美國隊
Switzerland, Great Britain, and the United States
組成這六支隊伍
round out the six.
來自華盛頓的男孩們離把金牌
The boys from Washington so close
帶回西雅圖僅有咫尺之遙
to bringing an Olympic title back to Seattle.
德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德國隊 德國隊 德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德國隊 德國隊 德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
德國隊德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland!
唐 你還好嗎
Don, you okay?
你可以的 唐 好嗎
You got this, Don, all right?
嘿 他說什麼
Hey, what'd he say?
好了 來吧 讓我們贏得勝利吧
All right. Come on, let's win this.
備槳
Oars ready.
來吧
Come on.
我們需要彌補兩段風
All right, we got two lengths of wind
的差距
to make up on this bunch.
所以 我們從38槳開始
So, we start at 38.
鮑比 鮑比
Bobby! Bobby!
該死 劃啊 劃啊
Shit! Row! Row!
加油
Come on.
天啊 他聽不到他的指令
Oh, God! He couldn't hear him.
美國隊跌跌撞撞地出發了 已然落後了一艘艇的距離
The Americans have stumbled out of the gate, already a full boat behind.
蹬腿
Legs through.
好了 現在降至30槳
All right, now move to 30.
劃啊 入水 破水
Go! In, through.
蹬腿
Legs through!
入水 破水 入水
In, through! In!
好了 你們做得很好
All right. We got 38!
給我40槳
Give me 40!
入水 破水
In, through!
入水 破水 衝啊
In, through! Go!
拜託 唐 振作起來
Come on, Don, pick it up.
腿發力 入水 破水
In the legs! In, through!
入水 破水
In, through!
- 入水 破水 - 是時候行動了
- In, through! - It's time to move!
來吧 唐
Come on, Don.
Go, Don!
快啊 孩子們
Come on, boys.
德國隊位於意大利隊之後
Germany is just behind Italy,
大不列顛隊緊隨其後
followed by Great Britain.
美國隊仍位於最後 遠遠落後於匈牙利隊
The U.S. still in last, well behind Hungary.
必須提高槳頻
Give me more! Gotta have more!
來呀 唐 給我40槳
Come on, Don. Give me 40.
腿發力
In the legs.
- 用力 唐 - 來吧 唐
- Push it, Don. - Come on, Don!
現在再合適不過了 休謨
Now would be a good time, Hume!
來吧 唐 振作起來
Come on, Don! Pick it up!
唐 來吧
Don, come on.
來吧 唐
Come on, Don.
拜託 唐
你得給我40槳 你可以的
Gotta give me 40. You have it.
給我吧
Give it to me.
來吧 給我40槳
Come on, give me 40.
來啊 唐
Come on, Don.
來啊
Come on!
唐
Don!
唐 來吧
Don! Come on!
每天早上 每天晚上
Every morning, every evening
我們不是很開心嗎
Ain't we got fun?
錢財不多 但親愛的
Not much money, oh, but honey
我們不是...
Ain't we got...
這就對了 唐 給我40槳
That's right, Don! Give me 40!
入水 破水
Go! Through!
蹬腿
Legs through!
抬頭
Eyes up!
放低
Stay low!
- 保持放鬆 - 終於
- Stay loose! - And here comes
美國隊迎來了一次爆發
the United States with a burst.
劃
Row!
上下一心
As one!
在靠近500米標記點處
Nearing the 500- meter mark,
美國隊追趕上了
the Americans have caught up
匈牙利隊和瑞士隊
to the Hungarian and Swiss teams.
保持住
Stay!
破水 入水 破水
And through! In, through!
美國隊超越了
The Americans have overtaken
瑞士隊和匈牙利隊
the Swiss and the Hungarian boats.
德國隊與意大利隊並列領先
Germany and Italy share the lead,
大不列顛隊尾隨其後
with Great Britain trailing.
腿放鬆
Legs loose!
入水 破水
In, through!
In and through!
四 五
Four! Five!
入水 破水
In, through!
給我42槳
Give me 42!
馬上
Now!
入水 破水
In, through!
深呼吸
Breathe!
- 蹬腿 - 入水 破水
- Legs through! - In, through!
再來十五槳 入水
Fifteen more! In!
- 快啊 - 破水
- Come on. - Through!
再來十槳
Ten more!
肩膀放低 保持鬆弛
Shoulders down and loose.
槳抬高
Stand tall!
入水 破水
In, through!
美國隊持續發力
And the Americans continue strong,
超越大不列顛隊 位列第三
moving past Great Britain and headed for third.
美國隊正朝著金牌邁進
The U.S. is moving into medal position.
破水 抬頭
Through! Eyes up!
入水 破水
In, through!
給我46槳
Give me 46!
沖
Go!
最後三百米 美國隊
300 meters, and the Americans
已齊頭並進
have pulled even!
三條艇並駕齊驅 還剩兩百五十米
The boats are three across now. 250 meters to go.
- 加油 加油 加油 - 蹬腿
- Come on, come on, come on. - Legs through!
三條艇不分上下
It's a three- boat race.
哪支隊伍會率先突出重圍
Who's going to break?
德國隊 意大利隊
It's Germany, Italy.
意大利隊 德國隊
Italy, Germany.
美國隊 意大利隊
The U.S. and Italy.
旗鼓相當 不分伯仲啊
It's just too close.
放低
Stay low!
最後一百米
100 meters to go.
三條艇並駕齊驅
It's neck and neck.
來吧
Come on.
德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德國隊 德國隊 德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
入水 破水
In, through!
全力以赴 衝啊
Give it everything! Go!
保持專注
Stay central!
抬頭
Eyes up!
上下一心
As one!
打敗你前面的人
Off the man in front of you!
入水 破水
In, through!
Go! In, through!
抬頭
Eyes up!
腿發力
In the legs!
德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德國隊 意大利隊 美國隊
Germany, Italy, America.
德國隊 德國隊
Deutschland! Deutschland!
比賽落下帷幕
And that's it!
一切已成定局
That's it!
結果過於接近 通訊員無法判斷
The results are just too close for this reporter to tell.
來吧
Come on.
誰贏了
Who won?
德國的粉絲相信
The German fans believe
這是他們在1936年奧運會上的第六次勝利
they've got their sixth win of these 1936 Olympics.
我們只能靜待結果出爐
We can only sit and wait for the results.
你看到了嗎
Did you see?
美國隊
America.
美國隊贏得了金牌
The United States has won the gold!
好樣的 約翰尼
Good job, Johnny.
我們成功了 兄弟們
We did it, boys!
來吧
Come on!
好一個領槳手
One hell of a stroke.
美國隊做到了
America has done it!
他們摘下了金牌
They've won the gold!
多麼經常的比賽
Hell of a race.
- 你做的了 艾爾 你成功了 - 我為你自豪
- You did it, Al. You did it. - I'm proud of you.
我們成功了
We did it.
瞧瞧啊
How about this, huh?
你好好瞧瞧
Mm- hmm. How about this?
你有什麼想說的嗎 艾爾
Anything you'd like to say about those boys, Al?
他們是我見過的最優秀的艇員
They are the finest I ever saw seated in a shell.
還不賴 對吧 夥計們
Not bad, huh, fellas?
你看到了嗎
Did you see that?
艇徑直把我推向了岸邊
Boat pushed me right into the bank.
- 看這團糟 - 別擔心 我們會修好的
- Look at this. - Don't worry, we'll fix it.
嘿 爺爺
Hey, Grandpa?
你覺得有一天我也會去划艇嗎
You think someday I can row crew?
這個嘛 你得堅持下去
Well, you gotta keep at it.
你喜歡劃八人艇嗎
Did you like rowing eight- man crew?
- 八人艇嗎 - 對
- Eight? - Yeah.
我們八人
We were never eight.
有如一體
We were one.